music
音楽
are still here listening to this speech
今もここでこのスピーチを聞いています
It takes a lot of enthusiasm
かなりの熱意が必要です
so first of all congratulations
だからまずはおめでとう
Our lecture today is sponsored by the Institute of Culture and Philosophy, Academia Sinica
今日の講演は中央研究院文化哲学研究所の後援によるものです。
Director Hu Xiaozhen
所長胡小真所長
to give a lecture
講義をする
Director Hu is one of the youngest directors of Academia Sinica
胡所長は中央研究院の最年少所長の一人である
It should be the youngest
最年少のはずだよ
But I don't know that the director of the chemistry department may be younger than you
でも、化学部の部長があなたより若いかもしれないとは知りません
Then the famous rich woman
すると、有名な金持ちの女性が
Rich women are also one of the subjects of his research
裕福な女性も彼の研究対象の一つです
Director Hu is a graduate of National Taiwan University
胡監督は国立台湾大学卒業生
Then go to the UCC Provincial Union to study for a master's degree
その後、UCC 州連合に行き、修士号取得のために勉強します。
Then went to Harvard University to get a Ph.D.
その後、博士号を取得するためにハーバード大学に進学しました。
This is what a rich woman should have.
これは裕福な女性が持つべきものです。
Then his research direction
その後、彼の研究の方向性は
related to women
女性に関係するもの
his three directions
他的三個方向
The first is young women's literature
まずは若い女性文学です。
I think you have many
たくさん持っていると思います
may have noted his famous book in this regard
この点に関して彼の有名な本に注目したかもしれない
It is inevitable for a rich woman to test her career
裕福な女性が自分のキャリアを試すのは避けられない
The Scheming of Modern Chinese Women's Narrative Literature
現代中国女性物語文学の構想
It was in early 2003
それは 2003 年の初めのことでした
His second principle is
彼の第二の原則は、
Re-exploring the conflict and fusion between Ming and Qing literature and modern literature
明清文学と近代文学の対立と融合を再探求する
Under this topic, he wrote a book "Society where mental ideals and physical strength cannot be amnesiac".
このテーマのもと、著書『精神的理想も体力も記憶喪失にならない社会』を執筆。
This book was published in 2011
この本は2011年に出版されました
get 2012 soon
2012年が早く来ますように
Academia Sinica's first Humanities and Social Sciences Special Book Award
中央研究院第1回人文社会科学特別図書賞
The third direction of research is his recent research
研究の 3 番目の方向性は彼の最近の研究です
I haven't seen any literature on this
これに関する文献は見たことがありません
But maybe already, I don't know
でも、もしかしたらすでにそうなっているかもしれない、分からない
It is to study the presentation of Southwest China by young literati
若い文人による中国西南部の表現を学ぶことです
Well, there are very few researchers on this topic
まあ、このテーマに関する研究者はほとんどいません
must be interesting
きっと面白いはず
Chief Hu has received many honors including this
胡主席はこれを含む多くの栄誉を受けている
Youth of Academia Sinica in 1999
1999年中央研究院青年期
Scholar Research Work Award
学術研究功績賞
2003 Wu Daer Award of the National Science Council
2003 年国家科学会議呉大爾賞
And the 2012 I just reported to you
そして先ほど報告した2012年
The First Humanities and Social Sciences Special Book Award
第1回人文・社会科学専門図書賞
He also invited the International Conference of Japanese Orientalists in Japan
彼はまた、日本の東洋学者の国際会議を日本に招待した。
The keynote speech
基調講演の様子
This is also an honor that is not easy to get.
これも簡単には得られない栄誉です。
The topic of Mr. Hu's speech today is Chinese women's travel experience
今日の胡氏のスピーチのテーマは中国人女性の旅行体験です。
From Ming and Qing Dynasties to Early Ming Dynasty
明清時代から明時代初期まで
I think this topic is quite interesting
このテーマはかなり興味深いと思います
Because ancient women seem to travel less
古代の女性はあまり旅行をしなかったようだから
so this is a
これは
Research in this area is not easy
この分野の研究は簡単ではありません
The second trip is a very attractive thing for many people
二度目の旅行は多くの人にとってとても魅力的なものです
I am a colleague of the History Institute of China-Ireland Studies
私は中国・アイルランド歴史研究所の同僚です。
We used to have an old director
昔、古い監督がいました
He is now in his 80s
彼は現在80代です
I asked him why did you devote yourself to history?
私は彼になぜ歴史に専念したのかと尋ねました。
He said that when he was studying in Yizu School in Nanjing
彼は南京の宜津学校に留学していたときにこう言った。
My favorite is to go to a small hotel at the front to see the registration department of the hotel
私のお気に入りは、フロントにある小さなホテルに行って、ホテルの登録部門を見ることです。
Registry Department
登記部
from where to where to go
どこからどこへ行くのか
its history is not
その歴史はそうではありません
Let's learn where we come from and where we go
私たちがどこから来て、どこへ行くのかを学びましょう
So it has since decided to study history
そこで歴史を勉強することにしました
so this story i keep telling
だから私が語り続けるこの物語
In the future, when I write an article, I should start with this
今後記事を書くときはこれから始めよう
so travel
だから旅行する
travel hotels etc. are very
旅行ホテルなどはとても良いです
big has a lot of imagination
ビッグは想像力が豊かです
very interesting topic
とても興味深い話題
so i think many people come today
今日はたくさんの人が来ると思います
It's all because he was deeply attracted by Chief Hu's personal dismissal
胡主席の個人的解任に深く惹かれたからだ
and the attraction of this topic
そしてこの話題の魅力
I won't say much now
今はあまり言いません
We now welcome Chief Hu with applause
胡主席を拍手でお迎えします
ask yuma
ユマに聞いてください
Just now Dean Wang Fei mentioned
たった今、ディーン・ワン・フェイが言及しました
Today is such a wet and cold winter day
今日はとても雨が多くて寒い冬の日です
and still this
そしてまだこれ
It's Friday night, the eve of the holiday.
休日の前夜の金曜日の夜です。
Well in fact I just got
まあ実際のところ、私はちょうど得た
This task in the courtyard
中庭でのこの作業
I don't know the seriousness of this matter
この問題の深刻さがわかりません
I just know it's the end of December
気づけばもう12月も終わりですね
I found out later that it was December 24th
後で知ったのですが、12月24日でした
I thought to myself that this task is too difficult.
この仕事は難しすぎると私は思いました。
So how can we have a topic that can attract everyone?
では、どうすれば誰もが惹きつけられる話題を持てるのでしょうか？
How about coming to Academia Sinica on such a day?
そんな日は中央研究院に来てみてはいかがでしょうか？
So the vice president just mentioned
それで、先ほど副大統領が言いました
Chinese women in our impression
私たちの印象に残る中国人女性
Isn't it very fulfilling?
とても充実しているのではないでしょうか？
so let's talk
それで話しましょう
Chinese Women's Fulfillment Experience
中国人女性の充実体験
Surely this deceitful subject
きっとこの欺瞞的な主題
You can fool everyone
みんなを騙せるよ
So obviously it seems to have had some success
明らかに一定の成功を収めているようです
So
それで
Although my topic is customized
私のトピックはカスタマイズされていますが、
Chinese Women's Fulfillment Experience
中国人女性の充実体験
But I really have to start by saying
しかし、本当に最初に言わなければならないのは、
There's absolutely no way this speech can be put together for you.
このスピーチをあなたのために組み立てることは絶対に不可能です。
Or crawling books or talking about
本を読みあさったり、それについて話したり
This millennium or this hundreds of years
この千年、あるいはこの数百年
of Chinese women's experience with this fulfillment
中国人女性のこの充実感の経験
no way to do a full description
完全な説明を行う方法はありません
Of course, a big reason for this is that
もちろん、その大きな理由としては、
i'm not a historian at all
私は全く歴史家ではありません
I'm actually noticing
実は気づいてるんです
this historian is doing
この歴史家はやっている
makes me feel very nervous
とても緊張する
i am not a historian
私は歴史家ではありません
There is no way to do this description historically
歴史的にこの説明を行う方法はありません
So what should I say I really want to talk about?
では、本当に話したいことは何と言えばいいのでしょうか？
Is it a woman who travels
旅行するのは女性ですか
how to travel
どうやって旅行するの
What means of transportation did you use to travel?
旅行にどのような交通手段を使いましたか?
where did you travel
どこに旅行に行ったの
Or must have seen something, etc. These questions
あるいは何かを見たことがあるに違いないなど、これらの質問
because I study literature
私は文学を勉強しているので
what i want to talk about
私が話したいこと
It should be said that it is a literary work, how to write it
文学作品と言うべきか、どう書くか
this woman's journey
この女性の旅
And when the woman's trip actually happened
そして女性旅行が実際に起こったとき
What about this trip and his writing
この旅行と彼の著作についてはどうですか
What effect will it have?
どのような効果がありますか?
This is the question I want to know
これが私が知りたい質問です
So today I will talk about a special woman
そこで今日は特別な女性について話します
from her life
彼女の人生から
From her travel experience
彼女の旅行経験から
And her writing in the mail?
そして彼女のメールの文面は？
start as core
コアとしてスタートする
then spread out
それから広げます
Trying to describe my travels with Chinese women
中国人女性との旅行について説明しようとしています
An Observation on the Problem of Travel
旅行の問題に関する考察
well then
じゃあ
sorry
ごめん
Okay, so let's start with this twentieth-century
さて、それではこの 20 世紀から始めましょう
once very very famous one
かつてとてもとても有名だった
Women's Tour Begins
女子ツアー開幕
so who is this woman
それで、この女性は誰ですか
Her name is Lu Bicheng
彼女の名前はルー・ビチェンです
Lu Bicheng was born in 1883
ルー・ビチェンは1883年生まれ。
Then the one who died in 1943
それから1943年に亡くなった人
So it's basically this pro-Wo Mingchu period guy
つまり、基本的にはこの親呉明中時代の人です
Then she was really famous at the time
それから彼女は当時とても有名な人でした
a rich woman writer
一個財女作家
also an educator
教育者でもある
also a tourist
観光客でもある
Then her life is very, very wonderful
それなら彼女の人生はとてもとても素晴らしいです
We can almost say there's something about her
彼女については何かがあると言ってもいいでしょう
It's just that nothing is ordinary
ただ、何も普通ではないのです
Her life is spent with extraordinary
彼女の人生は並外れたもので過ごします
to define
定義します
Then she was born in Anhui
その後、彼女は安徽省で生まれました
This is still my same
これは今でも私と同じです
Datong Township
大同鎮
A late man in Anhui, one key family
安徽省の亡くなった男性、重要な家族の1人
So we can say that her early life
したがって、彼女の初期の人生は
is a standard Guixiu
標準的なGuixiuです
Like those mentioned in my previous research
以前の研究で言及したものと同様
The Guixiu rich girl in the Ming and Qing Dynasties is the same
明清時代の貴秀の金持ち娘は同じです
she was born in a good family
彼女は良い家庭に生まれました
Father is an official, mother knows how to take care of books and is literate
父親は役人、母親は本の扱い方を知っており、読み書きができる
teach her to read and write
彼女に読み書きを教える
There is a very good private library in the house
家にはとても充実した私設図書館があります
She can study golden shit by herself since she was a child
彼女は子供の頃から自分で黄金のことを勉強することができます
Probably such a background
たぶんそういう背景があるんだろうな
But what?
でも何？
Lu Licheng, she is more unfortunate
ルー・リーチェン、彼女はもっと不幸だ
Her father died when she was very young
彼女の父親は彼女が幼い頃に亡くなった
Then there were some disputes in her family.
その後、彼女の家族内でいくつかの争いが起こりました。
So they can no longer gain a foothold in their hometown
そのため彼らは故郷に足がかりを築くことができなくなりました
then her mother wants
それから彼女の母親は望んでいます
Lu Licheng can live and work in peace
Lu Licheng は平和に暮らし、働くことができます
further education is available
さらなる教育が受けられます
sent Lu Licheng to her uncle's house
陸麗成を叔父の家に送った
Where is this uncle's house?
このおじさんの家はどこですか？
In a place called Tanggu
塘沽という場所で
Of course this is not far from Tianjin
もちろん、ここは天津からそれほど遠くありません
So obviously Lu Licheng is there
明らかにルー・リーチェンがそこにいる
She continues to grow her this
彼女はこの先も成長し続ける
this classical aspect of this
この古典的な側面
Ability to read and write
読み書きができる能力
But when he was about 20 years old
しかし、彼が20歳くらいのとき、
He has a renewed desire
彼は新たな願望を抱いている
what is this wish
この願いは何ですか
It is that he hopes to go to a bigger place
それは彼がもっと大きな場所に行きたいと思っているということです
go and see
行って見ろよ
what happened in the new place
新しい場所で何が起こったのか
Especially new women's schools
特に新設女子校は
Appeared in China at this time
この頃中国に出現
What do women's schools teach?
女子校では何を教えているのでしょうか？
Lu Bicheng has a new wish in her heart
ルー・ビチェンは心の中に新たな願いを抱いている
so he decided
それで彼は決めた
to the nearest big city
一番近い大都市まで
That is Tianjin to see
それが天津です
What is the so-called new style of women's school?
いわゆる新しいスタイルの女子校とは何でしょうか？
Then at this time he received
そしてこの時彼は受け取った
resistance of very very large families
非常に大家族の抵抗
that is his uncle
それは彼の叔父です
with a more traditional way of thinking
より伝統的な考え方で
of course stop him
もちろん彼を止めてください
Then this Lu Bicheng
それからこのルー・ビチェン
seems for the record
記録用のようです
He's been a boy since he was little
彼は小さい頃から男の子だった
a girl
女の子
It is more dispatchable
より発送可能です
So he was so angry
それで彼はとても怒っていました
just ran away from home
ちょうど家から逃げ出したばかり
What's even more frightening?
さらに恐ろしいことは何でしょうか？
when he ran away from home
彼が家から逃げたとき
bring nothing
何も持ってこない
according to his own statement
彼自身の声明によると
he confiscated the luggage
彼は荷物を没収した
no money
お金がない
I got on the train alone
一人で電車に乗りました
going to tianjin
天津に行きます
Then this may well be the beginning of a tragedy
そうなると、これは悲劇の始まりかもしれない
right
右
But Lu Bicheng is still very lucky
しかし、ルー・ビチェンはまだ非常に幸運です
he is on this train
彼はこの電車に乗っています
met a
に会った
A nobleman who helped him a lot
彼を大いに助けてくれた貴族
who is this person
このひとはだれ
Let's see Lu Bicheng's life
ルー・ビチェンの生涯を見てみましょう
from this time on
今回から
Just have an indissoluble bond with Lu Xingjie
Lu Xingjie との切っても切れない絆を持ってください。
Who is this noble man he knows?
彼の知っているこの高貴な男は誰ですか？
It is a famous hotel in Tianjin
天津の有名なホテルです
Mistress of Fozhaolou
法照楼の女主人
So
それで
And we also found that Lu Bicheng
そして、Lu Bicheng も発見しました。
He obviously has an innate ability
彼には明らかに天性の才能がある
He can explain different people on the journey
彼は旅の途中でさまざまな人々について説明することができる
if i guess if i were on the train
もし私が電車に乗っていたとしたら
I might just go all the way to the empty city
誰もいない街まで行ってみようかな
just no one cares about me
ただ誰も私のことなんて気にしてないだけ
But Lu Bicheng is on the train
しかしルー・ビチェンは電車に乗っている
be able to explain to a stranger
見知らぬ人に説明できる
and help him
そして彼を助けてください
so what
だから何
This Lu Bi achievement follows this
このLu Biの功績はこれに続きます
Fozhaolou Hotel
フォジャオロウ ホテル
The proprietress has arrived in Tianjin
女将さんが天津に到着しました
And what?
そして何？
The hostess also introduced him
女主人も彼を紹介してくれました
a more important person
もっと大切な人
It's Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェンです
Who was it? That was from the Tianjin Ta Kung Pao at that time.
誰だったかというと、当時の天津大公報だった。
This is like saying boss
これは上司と言っているようなものです
Eagle chain weaving
イーグルチェーンウィービング
So what about this eagle chain weaving?
では、この鷲の鎖編みはどうでしょうか？
After reading this letter that Lu Bicheng offered to him,
魯碧成が彼に差し出したこの手紙を読んだ後、
What about after the poem?
詩の後はどうでしょうか？
He said such a young girl
彼はこんな若い女の子に言った
able to write such a good article
こんなに良い記事を書くことができます
very very touched
とてもとても感動しました
So what about this eagle chain weaving?
では、この鷲の鎖編みはどうでしょうか？
Just ran to this Fozhao Tower to find Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェンを見つけるためにこの仏照塔に走ったところです
And what about inviting him to write for this Ta Kung Pao
そして、このタ・クン・パオに彼を招待するのはどうですか？
writing
書き込み
So from now on, what about Lu Bicheng?
さて、今後、ルー・ビチェンはどうなりますか？
It's like starting to explore the world in Tianjin
天津から世界を探検し始めるようなものです
So he started writing for this paper?
それで彼はこの新聞に書き始めたのでしょうか？
be an editor, wait
編集者になってください、待ってください
so because of
だから
He is so rich
彼はとてもお金持ちです
What I wrote made a lot of this
私が書いたことがこれの多くを生み出しました
this text
このテキスト
This is it
これだよ
celebrity
有名人
This man of letters
この文豪は
are very very shocked
とてもとてもショックを受けています
So he quickly
それで彼はすぐに
In the area of ​​Beijing and Tianjin
北京・天津エリアでは
want to be very famous
とても有名になりたい
He also had contacts with many famous literati
彼は多くの著名な文人たちとも交流があった
Everyone sees this time
今度はみんな見てね
When I first arrived in Tianjin and entered Ta Kung Pao
初めて天津に来て大公寶に入ったとき
On the left is Lu Bicheng
左がルー・ビチェンさん
The one on the right is the lady of the theater
右の人は劇場のお姉さんです
I'm sorry, is there a problem?
申し訳ありませんが、何か問題はありますか？
OK good
いいよ
Lu Bicheng had some other experiences after this
ルー・ビチェンはこの後もいくつかの経験をしました
He once entered Yuan Shikai's government
彼は袁世凱の政府に入ったこともある
served as Yuan Shikai's secretary
袁世凱の秘書を務めた
And a more special experience is
そして、さらに特別な体験は、
in 1906
1906年に
In fact, he was in his early 20s at this time.
実際、この時彼は20代前半でした。
only 23 years old
まだ23歳
In our case, a college graduate
私たちの場合は大学卒業生です
but he has accepted
しかし彼は受け入れました
It is equivalent to accepting Yuan Shikai's commission
袁世凱の依頼を受けたに等しい
went to do one
一つやりに行った
It is considered a very early high school in the north
北部では非常に初期の高校と考えられています
beiyang woman
北陽の女性
It is a model school
モデル校です
And what?
そして何？
He soon became the school's
彼はすぐに学校の責任者になりました
called supervision
監督と呼ばれる
That's what we mean today
それが今日の意味です
It's the principal
校長です
so what
だから何
What about Lu Bicheng in the 1910s
1910年代の魯碧成についてはどうだったでしょうか
He is actually a
実は彼は、
Educator Identity for Girls' Education
女子教育における教育者のアイデンティティ
such an image appears
そんなイメージが出てくる
good
良い
then but
それからしかし
During this time he wrote a lot
この間、彼はたくさんのことを書きました
sing girl
提唱女學呀
What is this song about saving the country and the people?
国と国民を救うこの歌は何ですか？
what kind of articles
どのような記事ですか
But what?
でも何？
He didn't actually play such a role.
彼は実際にはそのような役割を果たしませんでした。
too long
長すぎる
after a few years
数年後
He left the circle
彼はサークルを去った
then start
それから始めます
Another image appeared
別の画像が出てきました
he arrived in shanghai
彼は上海に到着しました
Become a foreign businessman like this
こんな外資系ビジネスマンになる
what a person doing business
なんてビジネスマンなんだ
And what?
そして何？
lady is very smart
女性はとても賢いです
he is fast
彼は速いです
really made money
本当に儲かった
living a very luxurious life
とても贅沢な生活を送っている
And what?
そして何？
after this
この後
He started to have some travel experience
彼は旅行の経験を持ち始めた
then compare
それから比較してください
we may be able to say unbelief
私たちは不信仰と言えるかもしれない
After this Lu Bicheng can even say
この後、Lu Bicheng は次のようにも言えます。
She's been homeless all her life.
彼女は生涯ホームレスだった。
She keeps wandering in different places
彼女はさまざまな場所をさまよい続けます
because of some other special factors
他の特殊な要因があるため
We don't have time here so I won't mention it
ここでは時間がないので言及しません
In fact, Lu Bicheng has never been married in his life.
実際、ルー・ビチェンは生涯結婚したことがありません。
So I guess it doesn't have to be in the same place as her
だから彼女と同じ場所にいる必要はないと思う
Then walking around still has a certain relationship
歩き回ることにはまだ一定の関係がある
Then from 1918 to 1922
その後、1918 年から 1922 年まで
Of course, everyone think about this time
もちろん、今回のことはみんな考えてるよ
The May Fourth Movement was in 1919
五四運動は1919年に起きた
Then when she was from 1918 to 1922
それから彼女が1918年から1922年までの頃
That is, before and after the May 4th News Movement
つまり、5.4ニュース運動の前後です。
Lu Bicheng went to Columbia University in New York to audit and study
Lu Bicheng は監査と研究のためにニューヨークのコロンビア大学に行きました
Let's take a look, this is Lu Bicheng from the Columbia period
見てみましょう、これはコロンビア時代のルー・ビチェンです
Can you imagine this is an international student?
これが留学生だと想像できますか？
So where does this claim come from?
では、この主張はどこから来たのでしょうか?
In fact after his death
実は彼の死後、
There are records left by some religious friends who have been with him
彼と一緒にいた何人かの宗教的な友人が残した記録があります
So it is said that after Lu Bicheng arrived in New York?
つまり、ルー・ビチェンがニューヨークに到着した後だと言われていますか？
where does he live he doesn't live in a school dormitory
彼はどこに住んでいますか、学校の寮に住んでいません
He might not even have a formal semester
彼には正式な学期さえないかもしれない
He lives in a big hotel in a big hotel in New York
彼はニューヨークの大きなホテルに住んでいます
And it is said that this Lu Bicheng's room where he lived
そして、ルー・ビチェンが住んでいた部屋と言われています
Incredibly big
信じられないほど大きい
The rent in this hotel is the most expensive in the whole hotel
このホテルの家賃はホテル全体の中で一番高いです
What if the average Westerner lives in such a place?
平均的な西洋人がそのような場所に住んでいたらどうなるでしょうか？
Only stay for about a week at most
滞在期間はせいぜい1週間程度
maybe there's no money left
もしかしたらお金が残っていないかもしれない
But where did Lu Bicheng live at that time?
しかし、当時、魯碧成はどこに住んでいたのでしょうか？
But you can live here for six months
でもここに半年住めるよ
And what about the lady-in-waiting of New York City at the time?
当時のニューヨーク市の女官はどうだったのでしょうか？
Everyone heard his name
誰もが彼の名前を聞いた
Come to him again and hope to be friends with him
もう一度彼のところに来て、友達になれることを願っています
And whenever there is a banquet
そして宴会があるたびに
What's the classic? Wait.
古典的なものは何ですか? ちょっと待ってください。
It's an honor to ask him to participate.
彼に参加をお願いできて光栄です。
Then Li Yucheng responded to everyone's warm hospitality
そして、李玉成さんは皆さんの温かいおもてなしに応えました。
So he keeps making beautiful new clothes
だから彼は美しい新しい服を作り続けます
Maybe it's like the JC you see now
もしかしたら今のJCのようなものかもしれない
He makes all kinds of beautiful clothes
彼はあらゆる種類の美しい服を作ります
So if he goes to several parties a day
そうですね、彼が 1 日にいくつかのパーティーに行くとしたら
he keeps changing clothes
彼は着替え続けます
Just like a bride coming out of a room
まるで部屋から出てくる花嫁のように
Every banquet needs to change into different clothes
宴会ごとに違う衣装に着替える必要がある
And according to the record, his clothes are bright and colorful
そして記録によると、彼の服は明るくてカラフルです
Everyone who saw him thought he was a celestial being
彼を見た人は皆、彼を天人だと思った
Appearing like a fairy
妖精のような登場
such a person
そんな人
We probably don't imagine being an international student
私たちは留学生になることを想像していないかもしれません
because in our today's terminology
なぜなら、今日の用語では
We will say this is called public grievance
これを国民の苦情と呼ぶことにします
This is called social grievance
これを社会的不満といいます
So
それで
So what about his Kobe image?
では、彼のコービーイメージはどうなのでしょうか？
I think it's a social
それは社会的なものだと思う
Including Celebrities Home Talented Women Writers
セレブを含む ホーム 才能ある女性作家
such an image
そんなイメージ
We also think he looks like a phobia
私たちは彼が恐怖症のように見えるとも思います
he's been like this all his life
彼は生まれてからずっとこうだった
On the one hand, he pays great attention to his own image.
一方で、彼は自分自身のイメージに細心の注意を払っています。
like self-pity
自己憐憫
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
We know his life is after the middle eye
私たちは彼の人生が中目の後であることを知っています
In fact, it is a Buddhist
実は仏教なんです
So he's on the one hand like a fear sparrow
つまり彼は一方では恐怖のスズメのようだ
admiring your own eyebrows
自分の眉毛を愛でる
In this respect, I am persistent in cultivating Buddhism.
この点において、私は仏教の修煉に粘り強く取り組んでいます。
To Hongfa
ホンファへ
To promote the protection of animals
動物の保護を推進するために
no killing etc.
殺生禁止など。
figure of a giantess
巨人の姿
Such a seemingly contradictory
そんな一見矛盾しているような
contradictory
矛盾した
two self-identities
二つの自己アイデンティティ
in his life
彼の人生の中で
from the beginning to the end
最初から最後まで
all the same
すべて同じ
Of course, Yu Sheng at this time
もちろん、この時点ではYu Sheng
This luxury, this luxurious image
この贅沢、この贅沢なイメージ
In fact, it was with him at the time
実はその時彼と一緒にいたのです
Europe and the United States
ヨーロッパとアメリカでは
The environment has something to do with it
環境も関係あるよな
we'll talk about that later
それについては後で話します
Then, after Lu Mishen graduated from Columbia University,
その後、ルー・ミーシェンがコロンビア大学を卒業した後、
back to china
中国に戻ります
Or is it presumably living a life of social prestige?
それともおそらく社会的名誉を求めて生きているのでしょうか？
But since 1926
しかし1926年以来
He also started to go to Europe and America alone
一人でヨーロッパやアメリカにも行き始めた
live a long and vigorous life
長く元気に生きる
Finally he went around and chose
最後に彼はぐるぐる回って選んだ
Live among the deep light and water colors of this Switzerland
このスイスの深い光と水の色の中で暮らす
Then he did not return to China until 1933
その後、1933年まで中国に戻りませんでした。
Then I lived in Beijing
それから私は北京に住んでいました
But soon because of this
でもこのせいですぐに
The outbreak of the war against Japan
対日戦争勃発
In order to avoid this action by the Japanese Tsinghua University
日本の清華大学のこの行動を避けるために
He went abroad again
彼はまた海外へ行った
Then I went through the wandering years again
それからまた放浪の日々を過ごした
So in the end he is in the state affairs of Hong Kong
結局彼は香港の国政に携わることになる
Then let's say that the Republic of China starred in this
では、中華民国がこの作品に主演したとしましょう。
famous most famous traveler
最も有名な最も有名な旅行者
What about civil travel?
民間旅行についてはどうですか？
refers to this
これを指します
Lu Bicheng's work from 1926 to 1933
1926 年から 1933 年までのルー・ビチェンの作品
The experience of this trip to Europe and America
今回の欧米旅行の経験
So why is this tour famous?
では、なぜこのツアーが有名なのでしょうか？
It wasn't that he was the only woman who went abroad
海外に行った女性は彼だけではなかった
It's because Lu Bicheng himself is famous
ルー・ビチェン自身が有名だからです
right
右
Well, it's not because no one really went abroad at that time.
まあ、当時は海外に行く人が誰もいなかったからではありません。
but because he himself went abroad while
それは彼自身も同時に海外に行っていたからだ。
He first announced in the newspaper that I was going abroad
彼は私が海外に行くことを初めて新聞で発表した
And I'm going to be writing a post for dear readers
そして、親愛なる読者のために記事を書くつもりです
So this is almost like a self-promotional move.
したがって、これはほとんど自己宣伝のようなものです。
He started traveling with himself
彼は自分自身と一緒に旅行を始めました
In places like Suncheon Times in Beijing and Danyue Magazine in Shanghai
北京の順天時報、上海の丹越誌などに掲載。
start serializing his post
彼の投稿の連載を開始する
so in this way
それで終わりです
The fame of this wit
この機知の名声
And he was such a rare woman at the time
そして彼は当時とても珍しい女性でした
alone
1人
Not with family, not with personal friends, etc.
家族とではなく、個人的な友人とではなく、など。
Travel alone in Europe and America
ヨーロッパとアメリカの一人旅
And it's a long-term self-help
そしてそれは長期的な自助努力です
such a legendary
そんな伝説的な
plus his own fortune
それに加えて彼自身の財産
His writing is so talented
彼の文章はとても才能がある
plus newspapers and magazines
プラス新聞や雑誌
flattery about the thing
そのことについてのお世辞
Synergy of various factors
さまざまな要素の相乗効果
This makes Lu Bicheng's travel notes in Europe and America
これにより、Lu Bicheng のヨーロッパとアメリカの旅行記が作成されました
already popular at the time
当時すでに人気があった
It is said that readers have strange expectations
読者は変な期待を抱くというが
I can see his travelogue
彼の旅行記を見ることができます
Not only increased the number of his travel notes published
彼の旅行記の出版数が増えただけではありません
Sales of these newspapers and magazines
これらの新聞や雑誌の販売
It even seems to have caused a lot of piracy
多くの著作権侵害を引き起こしているようです
just steal his work
彼の仕事を盗むだけ
He obviously didn't submit to this publication
彼は明らかにこの出版物に投稿しなかった
This publication put his work on it
この出版物には彼の作品が掲載されています
Then said he voted
それから投票したと言いました
or even worse
さらに悪いことに
just to steal his work
彼の仕事を盗むためだけに
Plus a lot of my own material
それに加えて私自身の素材もたくさんあります
then say this
それならこう言ってください
It's Lu Bicheng's
ルー・ビチェンさんです
or
また
It's obviously Lu Bicheng's name changed
明らかにLu Bichengの名前が変更されました
this was written by someone else
これは他の人が書いたものです
various behaviors
さまざまな行動
So what about Lu Bicheng?
では、ルー・ビチェンはどうでしょうか？
has been very harshly criticized
非常に厳しく批判されています
This is now this China this
これが今、これが中国です、これが
What about the behavior of the newspaper and magazine industry?
新聞・雑誌業界の動向はどうだろうか？
It's even scarier than this bandit
この盗賊よりも怖いです
What about Lu Bicheng's mail?
Lu Bicheng のメールはどうですか?
This is his Lu post from 1926 to 1933
これは 1926 年から 1933 年までの彼の Luyou です
But what?
でも何？
time this mailing was written
このメールが書かれた時刻
time of recording
録音時間
Around 1926 to 1930
1926年から1930年頃
then what
じゃあ何
pamphlet
パンフレット
this is us today
これが今日の私たちです
This difficult postage route to Europe and America that will be discussed later
ヨーロッパとアメリカへのこの困難な郵便ルートについては後で説明します
Then he has another name?
では、彼には別の名前があるのでしょうか？
Red Snow Dollar
ホンシュエ・インユアン
so sorry
ごめんなさい
Of course, what about the name in front of it?
もちろん、その前の名前はどうでしょうか？
It's more realistic
より現実的です
Because he just went to Europe and the United States to separate
だって彼はヨーロッパとアメリカに行って別れたばかりだから
What about the name Hongxue Yingyuan in the back?
後ろのHongxue Yingyuanという名前はどうですか？
It is entrusted to this Lu Bicheng
この呂備成に託される
some feelings of my own life
自分の人生についてのいくつかの感情
Then Lu Bicheng he from
それからルー・ビチェン彼は
Started writing in 1926
1926年に執筆を開始
And publish Europe and America roaming record
ヨーロッパとアメリカのローミング記録を公開
what is the type of his writing
彼の文章の種類は何ですか
or classical Chinese
または古典的な中国語
He still writes in classical Chinese
彼は今でも古典中国語で執筆しています
In fact, Lu Bicheng
実はルー・ビチェン
He never gave up classical Chinese
彼は古典中国語を決して諦めなかった
in the form of classical poetry
古典的な詩の形で
Then we know that he is a very important poetess in modern times
そうすれば、彼が現代において非常に重要な詩人であることがわかります。
Some people say that he is three hundred years old
彼は300歳だという人もいる
The most important and last female poetess
最も重要で最後の女流詩人
But this is already in 1926
しかし、これはすでに1926年のことです
30 years
30年
We all know what kind of times this is
今がどんな時代なのか私たちは皆知っています
This is already the era of vernacular people learning, right?
もう、バナキュラーな人々が学ぶ時代ですよね？
Didn’t the May Fourth News Movement happen in 1919?
五四ニュース運動は1919年に起こりましたよね?
Didn't the vernacular movement start a long time ago?
ヴァナキュラー運動はずっと前に始まったんじゃないの？
May Fourth novel that shouted not as early as 1923
1923 年には叫ばれなかった「五・四」の小説
already published?
すでに出版されていますか？
Peng Hong was published in 1926
『彭宏』は 1926 年に出版されました。
And two years later, in 1928,
そして2年後の1928年、
Hu Shi's vernacular
胡施の言葉
The first volume of literary history is about to appear
文学史の第一巻がまもなく登場
so it's a vernacular
だからそれは俗語です
an era of rising
上昇の時代
but
しかし
Lu Bicheng seems to be completely ignoring the trend of this era
盧碧成は時代の流れを完全に無視しているようだ
He still insists on writing in classical Chinese
彼は今でも漢文で書くことにこだわっている
He still has to write poems in the old style
彼は今でも古いスタイルで詩を書かなければなりません
old style words
古いスタイルの言葉
And what?
そして何？
in his text
彼の文章の中で
It's still such an allusion
それはまだそのような暗示です
I like beautifully crafted words
綺麗な言葉が好きです
Then we can't help but ask
それなら尋ねずにはいられません
why one so
なぜそうなるのか
seems to be very progressive
とても進歩的なようです
very independent
非常に独立した
will be bold
大胆になります
A person who went to Europe and America to roam for a long time by himself
ヨーロッパやアメリカに一人で長期間放浪した人
advanced women
先進的な女性
Then his literary creation
それから彼の文学作品は
or at least in his stylistic choices
少なくとも彼の文体の選択においては
why would he
なぜ彼は
seems so conservative
とても保守的に見える
so old fashioned
とても古風な
reluctance to accept new possibilities
新しい可能性を受け入れることに消極的になる
new trend
新しいトレンド
new things
新しいもの
Is there any contradiction in this?
これに矛盾はありますか？
If
もしも
We feel that experiments in literary creation
私たちは文学創作における実験を感じています
itself seems to be a kind of exodus
それ自体が一種の脱出であるように思われる
a kind of travel
一種の旅行
an expedition
遠征
a try
試してみる
a faraway word
遠い言葉
then on behavior
それから行動について
Willing to boldly go to Europe and America
果敢にヨーロッパやアメリカへ出ていきたい
Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェン
Why in the creation of his text
なぜ彼の文章を作成したのか
He never tried to go out and see
彼は決して外に出て見ようとはしなかった
That's what I'm curious about too.
それは私も気になるところです。
what about us for now
今のところ私たちはどうですか
Put this Lu Bi city aside
この魯美市を横に置いて
Leaving the 1920s for a while
1920年代からしばらく離れて
Then I want to share with you for a while
それでは、少しの間、皆さんと共有したいと思います
Let's go back to the women of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明と清の時代の女性に戻りましょう
Of course for us women today
もちろん現代の私たち女性にとっても
Travel is a long way
旅行は長い道のりです
a long history
昔何が起こったのか
in my friends
私の友達の中で
will go on a self-guided trip
セルフガイド旅行に行きます
Of course I haven't done statistics.
もちろん統計をとったわけではありません。
But I don't think it's good for women
でも女性には良くないと思う
more than men
男性よりも
But we often seem to feel
しかし、私たちはしばしばこう感じているようです
travel alone
一人旅
This is a constitutional fight woman
これが憲法闘争の女性です
have the right
権利がある
Because we always hear that women used to stay out of the house
昔は女性は家から出なかったとよく聞くから
Not bad for two
2人にとっては悪くない
but actually
でも実は
Even if we go back to the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明清の時代に戻っても
There are still many benefits
まだまだメリットはたくさんあります
There are still cases where women go out
女性が外出するケースもまだある
For example a female she can follow her father
たとえば、女性は父親に従うことができます。
The husband or even the son has gone to be an official somewhere else
夫や息子さえもどこか別の役人になってしまった
When her husband became an official, she followed her, etc.
夫が役人になると従ったなど。
This is called phantom
これをファントムといいます
Or if the person she's marrying lives far away
あるいは、結婚相手が遠方に住んでいる場合
Doesn't she have to go through a long and slow road before she can get married?
彼女は結婚するまでに長くて遅い道を通らなければならないのではないでしょうか？
this is a distant marriage
これは遠い結婚です
Then when she got married
それから彼女が結婚したとき
if she's going home to save time
彼女が時間を節約するために家に帰るなら
feelings this may need you too
これにはあなたも必要かもしれないという気持ち
even in some special cases
いくつかの特殊な場合でも
she may live for
彼女は生きるかもしれない
In order to maintain one's own livelihood
自分自身の生活を維持するために
and have to go to different places to teach
教えるために別の場所に行かなければなりません
Teach other people's children teach your students
他人の子供たちに教える 自分の生徒たちに教える
This is the so-called belonging poem
これはいわゆる所属詩です
What about an example like this?
このような例はどうでしょうか？
Of course, there were many during the Ming and Qing Dynasties
もちろん、明や清の時代にもたくさんありました
there are even more unfortunate things
さらに残念なことがあります
For example, if there is a war
例えば戦争が起きたら
Isn't that to escape?
それは逃げるためではないでしょうか？
In fact, escape is also a kind of travel
実は逃避も旅の一種なのです
of course
もちろん
We have a situation similar to our so-called tourism today.
今日のいわゆる観光業と同様の状況が起こっています。
that's still there
それはまだそこにあります
if not
そうでない場合
We would not be in the Ming and Qing travel poetry groups
私たちは明や清の旅行詩のグループには入らないでしょう。
see those sights
名所を見物します
Seeing the monuments and sending out feelings and so on works like this
モニュメントを見て気持ちを発信するなどの作品はこんな感じ
And if we talk about the comparison below the middle level
そして、中レベル以下の比較について言えば、
words from lower class women
下層階級の女性の言葉
Their activities will also include such activities as entering the incense group
香グループへの参入などの活動も予定
So in fact during the Ming and Qing Dynasties
実際、明と清の時代には
Women can still go out
女性はまだ外出できる
But today we will take one of them as an example.
しかし今日はそのうちの 1 つを例として取り上げます。
in light this
光の中でこれ
There is a very famous literati in the world
世界にとても有名な文人がいる
Yuan Mei
ユアン・メイ
That's more than eighteen people
それは18人以上です
This man certainly has all kinds of achievements.
この男は確かにあらゆる種類の功績を持っています。
but one thing
しかしそのうちの1人は
has always been the rear wheel
ずっと後輪だった
last until
まで続く
or comparable
または同等の
is that he has a habit
彼には癖があるということです
I just love accepting female disciples
女性の弟子を受け入れるのが大好きです
I love hanging out with female students
女子学生と遊ぶのが大好きです
After he stops being an official, of course he will be freer.
彼が公務員をやめれば、当然、より自由になるだろう。
He lives in this random
彼はこのランダムな世界で生きている
He will go to various places, such as Hangzhou and Suzhou
彼は杭州や蘇州などのさまざまな場所に行きます
Changshu, Songjiang, Zhengjiang, these places
常熟、松江、鄭江、これらの場所
Everywhere he goes
彼が行くところはどこでも
Those ones
それらです
recruited his name
彼の名前を募集した
this
これ
The female students will come to him
女子生徒たちが彼のところに来るだろう
to worship him as master
彼を師として崇拝する
He will be very happy to say that they are apprentices
彼は彼らが見習いだと言うととても喜んでくれるだろう
What about Yuan Mei? For these female disciples, this Chunyu is beautiful and very helpful to them.
袁美はどうですか? 女弟子たちにとって、この春雨は美しくてとても助けになります。
finally
ついに
He also changed a book for his female disciples called
彼はまた、女性の弟子のために『
The female disciple who followed the fate lost the election
運命を辿った女弟子は落選した
Of course they are not from the same place
もちろん同じ場所出身ではありません
I just mentioned a lot of place names
先ほどたくさんの地名を挙げましたが、
Although they are all in Jiangnan
みんな江南なのに
These female disciples are actually scattered in different places
この女性弟子たちは実は各地に散らばっているのです
But they will make an appointment with the original media teacher to meet in Hangzhou
しかし、彼らは元のメディア教師と杭州で会う約束をする予定です
They made an appointment to go to Hangzhou from various places
彼らは各地から杭州に行く約束をした
Gather together at West Lake
西湖に集合
And imitate male literati
そして男性文人の真似をする
Gather together in the form of West Lake elegant books to mention poems and sing
西湖の優雅な本の形で集まり、詩について言及したり歌ったりします
Then also solid professional people
それからしっかりとしたプロフェッショナルな人々も
Help them draw a picture of the situation they are dealing with
彼らが対処している状況の絵を描くのを手伝ってください
For example, you can see
たとえば、次のようになります。
which one to press
どれを押すか
can you see an old man here
ここにお年寄りが見えますか
This should be the original medium
これがオリジナルのメディアである必要があります
Then there are other women partying upstairs in West Lake
それから西湖の上の階では他の女性たちがパーティーをしています
They later called this saying "Hu Lou Asking for Karma"
彼らは後にこれを「カルマを求める胡楼」と呼んだ
The poems they made at that time are also included in this collection
その時に作った詩もこの詩集に収録されています
we can still see
私たちはまだ見ることができます
Of course examples like this are definitely not everyday
もちろん、このような例は決して日常的なものではありません
It's not something that can happen every few days
数日おきに起こることではない
But this example still shows
しかし、この例ではまだわかります
At that time, it was still possible for women of the home class to travel
当時はまだ家庭階級の女性が旅行することは可能でした。
In future generations, we are often subject to what we just said just now.
将来の世代では、私たちが今述べたことの影響を受けることがよくあります。
The effects of aging on the two sides
二門不脈的老化的影響
I thought this woman must never go out
この女は絶対に出てはいけないと思った
It is a historical reality that is released from all over the world and accepted
世界中から発信され受け入れられている史実です
But actually I think this is not quite accurate
しかし実際のところ、これはあまり正確ではないと思います。
Although the saying that Chinese women never travel is not very accurate
中国人女性は決して旅行しないという格言はあまり正確ではありませんが、
But at the level of discourse
しかし、談話のレベルでは
women have to walk out
女性は出て行かなければなりません
It is indeed a heart-to-heart exchange
まさに心と心の交流です
one thing
一件事情
we know popular literature
私たちは大衆文学を知っています
often best performing
多くの場合最高のパフォーマンスを発揮する
Some issues that people really care about
人々が本当に気にしているいくつかの問題
or a topic of interest
または興味のあるトピック
then we might as well
それなら私たちもそうするかもしれません
Give some examples from popular literature
一般的な文献から例をいくつか挙げてください
Vice President Wang just introduced
王副主席が先ほど紹介した
my first in this field of study
この分野の研究では初めて
women's literature of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明清時代の女性文学
Especially one created by women
特に女性が作ったものは
Novels with Yuwen titles
佳作を受賞した小説
Then it's called Tanci novel
それからそれはタンシ小説と呼ばれます
let me talk for a minute
ちょっと話させてください
what's the word
何だっけ
Tanci is originally a kind of musicality
Tanci はもともと音楽性の一種です
very nice
非常に素晴らしい
a rap literature
ラップ文学
this performer
この出演者
One side is about to bounce
片側が跳ね返ろうとしている
Sanxian
三県
or this person
またはこの人
Pipa is in the lower left corner
左下隅にあるのがピパです
rap and sing at the same time
ラップしたり歌いながら
to tell long stories
長い物語を語る
then this is in
それならこれは中にあります
Jiangnan area is a kind of
江南地域は一種の
very popular show
とても人気のある番組
especially popular with women
特に女性に人気がある
Then it was intentional at that time
じゃああの時は意図的だったのね
some women who can read world characters
世界の文字を読める女性もいる
They took advantage of this particular form
彼らはこの特殊な形式を利用しました
to create a dark-headed
暗い頭を作り出す
Can't really use it for performance
パフォーマンスにはあまり使えない
But you can watch it on your desk
でも机の上でも見れるよ
fiction for reading
読むためのフィクション
that's what i call this sting novel
それを私はこのスティング小説と呼んでいます
So as you can see in the upper left corner
左上隅にあるように、
This is a creation left over from the late Qing Dynasty
これは清朝末期の名残です。
Then you can see in the upper right corner
次に、右上隅にあるのがわかります
How much time has this woman spent in her life
この女性は人生でどれくらいの時間を費やしたのか
It's really a lifetime to write a novel
小説を書くのは本当に一生だ
This is their family heirloom handbook
これは彼らの家宝ハンドブックです
So what about stabbing novels?
では、刺し小説はどうでしょうか？
It basically uses the text to
基本的にテキストを使用して、
Narrative in seven fonts
7 つのフォントで物語を表現
So it's above the form
つまりフォームの上にあります
Certainly different from what we're used to
確かに私たちが慣れ親しんだものとは違います
Zhang Hui's novels in prose
張輝の散文小説
It's like pulling a kettle in the Three Kingdoms
まるで三国志のやかんを引くようなものだ
Journey to the West La Red Mansion these novels
西遊記 ラ・レッド・マンション この小説
but
しかし
Talking about stabbing novels also has Zhang Hui
刺す小説について語るなら張輝もいる
The same tells the full story
同じことがすべてを物語っています
Designs with characters and plots, etc.
キャラクターやストーリーなどをデザインしたもの。
so i think it's
だからそうだと思う
In fact a novel
実は小説
So
それで
What about the talk novel written by this female department?
この女性部が書いたトーク小説はどうでしょうか？
a large percentage
大きな割合
are telling a repeating story
繰り返しの物語を語っている
Then change from this tone
じゃあこの口調から変えて
what is this repeating story
この繰り返しの話は何ですか
That's what makes this story happen
それがこの物語を実現させる理由です
The heroines in the little book must leave his specifications
この小さな本のヒロインたちは彼の仕様を残さなければなりません
He's been staying home so there's no story
彼は家にいるから話がない
he must leave home
彼は家を出なければなりません
then to the public world
それから公の世界へ
so what to do
じゃあ何をすればいいの
They must first dress up as men
彼らはまず男性として服を着なければなりません
they tie up their hair
彼らは髪を結びます
to cover this piercing
このピアスを隠すために
to cover the little feet
小さな足を覆うために
put on men's boots
男性用のブーツを履く
Then Mai Kaibuzi went out
それからマイ・カイブジが出て行った
where are you going
どこに行くの
to the center of power
権力の中枢へ
where is that
それはどこですか
must be capital city
首都でなければなりません
because they want to fulfill their dreams
彼らは夢を叶えたいから
You must first obtain citizenship
まず市民権を取得する必要があります
So these languages ​​are as exceptional
したがって、これらの言語は同様に例外的です
Their destination is the center of power
彼らの目的地は権力の中枢
In Shenzhen, Meng Qianjun is like this. The female companion in men's clothes travels all the way from Yunnan to Beijing to take the exam.
深センの孟乾君はこんな感じで、男装の女性同行者は試験を受けるために雲南省から北京までやって来た。
For the heroines in such novels, their travels actually herald very drastic changes in their lives
このような小説のヒロインにとって、旅行は実際に人生の非常に劇的な変化を告げるものです。
They will play roles that only men in society should play for a long time
彼らは社会において男性だけが果たすべき役割を長く担っていくだろう
That is to be an official, a general, a parent, a husband, etc.
それは役人、将軍、親、夫などです。
And on their psychological level, these heroines hope that such a trip can go on forever
そして、心理レベルでは、ヒロインたちはそのような旅が永遠に続くことを望んでいます
so their travel has a big change
彼らの旅は大きな変化を迎える
Well, of course, with our travel set, we also hope to increase their travel
もちろん、私たちのトラベルセットで、彼らの旅行が増えることも期待しています。
that, of course, on their psychological level, these heroines hope that such a trip can go on forever
まあ、もちろん、心理的なレベルでは、これらのヒロインたちは旅が永遠に続くことを望んでいます
They will never need to go back to the norm to play the role of women in traditional society
彼らは伝統的な社会で女性の役割を果たすために標準に戻る必要は決してありません
chips their journey never has to end
彼らの旅に終わりはありません
The way we see it today, we can easily
今日の見方では、私たちは簡単にそれを行うことができます
It is easy to criticize these women writers
これらの女性作家を批判するのは簡単です
and the heroines they created
そして彼らが生み出したヒロインたち
Because they're just daydreaming, right?
だって彼らはただ空想しているだけですよね？
They never thought about resisting the system of traditional society
彼らは伝統的な社会のシステムに抵抗することを考えたこともありませんでした
Never really reflect on gender roles
男女の役割について深く考えないでください
Is it so fixed or not?
それほど固定されているのでしょうか？
Because these heroines they just want to be men
このヒロインたちはただ男になりたいだけだから
They didn't think about why the genders have such a division of labor
彼らは、なぜ男女がそのような役割分担をしているのかについて考えなかった
Is such criticism justified?
そのような批判は正当なのでしょうか？
Of course it makes sense, indeed.
確かに、それは当然のことです。
but i also want to ask
でも聞きたいこともあります
The women in these novels run away, the imagination of going out
小説の中の女性たちは逃げる、外出するという想像
Doesn't it represent a very deep spirit of pursuit?
とても深い探求心を表しているのではないでしょうか？
Isn’t this a person worthy of our understanding today?
これは今日の私たちが理解するに値する人物ではないでしょうか。
And a will to respect
そして尊重する意志
And not precisely because women so long ago
それは、女性がずっと昔にいたからというわけではありません。
a desire to have such an extreme pursuit
そのような極端な追求をしたいという願望
So after hundreds or hundreds of years to stimulate a new generation of women
何百年も経って、新しい世代の女性を刺激するために
For example, a woman like Lu Bicheng goes out
たとえば、ルー・ビチェンのような女性は外出します。
Then I think it is because of the novel about death written by Li Shiling
それは李世玲が書いた死についての小説のせいだと思います
This exodus and this longing, this soul that seeks
この出エジプトとこの憧れ、求めるこの魂
expressed so strongly
とても強く表現されました
So even in the novels about death written by Li Shi
だから李施が書いた死についての小説でも
There are also works that directly face the desire to go out and go out
外出したい、出かけたいという欲求と真正面から向き合った作品もある
the possible danger
起こり得る危険
Let's take a female work as an example
女性の仕事を例に挙げてみましょう
This work is Heaven and Flowers
この作品は『天国と花』です
The background of this talk about death is at the end of the Ming Dynasty
この死の話の背景は明末
Then the plot of this novel is combined with the historical events of the last years of the Ming Dynasty
そして、この小説のプロットは、明王朝末期の歴史的出来事と組み合わされています。
A family story with this
これで家族の物語
Then the plot is very rich
それからプロットは非常に豊かです
Of course it is impossible to explain to you here
もちろんここで説明することは不可能です
But there is a very special place in this novel
しかし、この小説には非常に特別な場所があります
It's that he keeps referring to women's going out
それは彼が女性の外出について言及し続けていることです
get out of this thing
このことから抜け出す
we have just said
私たちは今言ったばかりです
in the novel
小説の中で
If these hostesses don't leave the house
もしこのホステスたちが家から出なかったら
then there might be no story to tell
そうすれば語る話はなくなるかもしれない
But Tianyuhua is special
でも天羽華は特別です
Their heroine is at home
彼らのヒロインは家にいます
You can be a heroine without going out
外に出なくてもヒロインになれる
And the whole thing wants to say
そして全体が言いたいのは
repeatedly warns his readers
読者に繰り返し警告する
The danger of this woman going out
この女性が外出する危険性
There is a male protagonist in this novel
この小説には男性の主人公がいます
Zuo Weiming
左偉明
Not Du Weiming Zuo Weiming
デュ・ウェイミンではない ズオ・ウェイミン
But he is a great Confucian hero
しかし彼は偉大な儒教の英雄です
Today's Great Hero
今日の偉大なる英雄
He's pretty solid that women can't go out
彼は女性が外出できないとかなりしっかりしている
let's see what he said
彼が何と言ったか見てみましょう
This is Mr. Zuo Weiming Zuo
左偉明さんです。
he was a teenager himself
彼自身も十代だった
When I was not married and still a single man
まだ結婚しておらず独身だった頃
He ran to a consummation room by himself
彼は一人で成就の部屋に走った
Tour in the garden
庭園内ツアー
what about this time
今回はどうですか
he accidentally
彼は偶然
Met a girl who looks like a fairy
妖精のような女の子と出会った
And he heard the
そして彼はそれを聞いた
This lady's name is Ring Green Turtle
この女性の名前はリング・アオウミガメです
You can know it with a turtle
亀でわかるよ
should be in the tortoise
亀の中にいるはずだ
He went to see Miss Ring Green Turtle?
彼はミス・リング・アオウミガメに会いに行きましたか？
with his family
彼の家族と
Also play in the garden
庭でも遊べます
So Zuo Weiming thought in his heart
そこで左衛明は心の中でこう思った。
This green turtle
このアオウミガメ
Needless to say, talent and appearance
才能も容姿も言うまでもない
He is still the only one in the world
彼は今でも世界でただ一人です
but just
でもただ
he is a lady fairy
彼は妖精の女性です
Then he should stick to the door
それなら彼はドアに張り付くべきだ
Should I steal my identity?
私のアイデンティティを盗む必要がありますか?
How can I play outside with my mother?
どうしたらお母さんと一緒に外で遊べますか？
he went to peek by himself
彼は一人で覗きに行った
How about a young and beautiful girl?
若くて美しい女の子はどうでしょうか？
But I scold him in my heart
でも心の中で彼を叱る
can't come out
出られない
good
良い
So
それで
and after
以降
this
これ
once
一度
he is on his way
彼は向かっています
he met his friend
彼は友達に会った
this friend is a couple
この友人はカップルです
what about the husband
夫はどうですか
because
なぜなら
At the request of my wife, I brought my wife out
妻のリクエストで妻を連れて出かけました
Where do you go to burn incense when you go out?
外出するとき、どこでお香を焚きますか？
go on a pilgrimage to the mountain
山への巡礼に行く
He was robbed by bandits on the way
途中で山賊に盗まれました
Of course this beautiful lady almost lost her virginity
もちろん、この美しい女性はほぼ処女を失いました
Fortunately, the great hero Zuo Weiming saved them
幸いなことに、偉大な英雄、左維明が彼らを救ってくれました。
This is Zuo Ming's conclusion after saving them
これが彼らを救った後の左明の結論です
Not what he considers his male friend
彼が男友達だと思っているものではない
It's very embarrassing not being able to protect my wife
妻を守れなくてとても恥ずかしいです
his conclusion is
彼の結論は
It can be seen that Guiren can only be done in Guizhong
桂蓮は貴中でしかできないことが分かります
Can he go out in person?
彼は直接外出できますか？
look at
見る
It's because you're running out
足りなくなってきたからだよ
So today was hit by such a fire
さて、今日はそんな火災に見舞われました
you almost died
あなたはもう少しで死ぬところだった
You almost ended up in this pack of wolves and tigers
あなたは危うくこのオオカミとトラの群れに巻き込まれるところだった
There is no guarantee of the needle knot
針結びの保証はございません
this is his conclusion
これが彼の結論です
because or
なぜなら、または
this
これ
Later he got married
その後彼は結婚した
Miss Huang Qinghui who was criticized by him just now
先ほど彼に批判された黄清輝さん
later became his wife
後に彼の妻となった
then after marriage
それから結婚後
The unfortunate Miss Huang said
残念な黄さんはこう言いました。
I want to go home in two days
二日後には帰りたい
My mother said she would take me there
母は私をそこへ連れて行ってくれると言った
which garden to play
どの庭で遊ぶか
So this Zuo Weiming was furious
それでこの左衛明は激怒した
just tell him
ただ彼に言ってください
This is something that doesn't exist in our house
我が家には無いものです
Talking about mountains and playing with water is a man's business
山の話をしたり、水で遊んだりするのは男の仕事です
definitely not something women do
決して女性がやることではありません
That one can go outside
あの人は外に出てもいいよ
our family for generations
私たちの家族は何世代にもわたって
No one has ever done such a shameful thing
こんな恥ずかしいこと誰もやったことない
This is Zuo Weiming in Tian and Hua
天と華の左偉明です
He represents a spirit of this novel
彼はこの小説の精神を体現している
one he showed
彼が見せたもの
Restricting movement of women going out
女性の外出制限
an idea
アイデア
and more interestingly
そしてさらに興味深いことに
This Zuo Weiming
この左維明
Not only does he have to take care of his wife
彼は妻の世話をしなければならないだけでなく、
Of course he wants to take care of his daughter
もちろん彼は娘の世話をしたいと思っています
Not only can his daughter not go out
娘は外出できないだけでなく、
to explore the garden outside
外の庭を探索する
I can't even go to my own back garden.
自分の裏庭にも行けない。
Why can't you go to your own back garden?
なぜ自分の裏庭に行けないのですか？
Of course you can imagine
もちろん想像できるでしょう
How did the story of Wu Dantian happen?
武丹田の物語はどのようにして起こったのでしょうか？
The back garden is a very dangerous place
裏庭はとても危険な場所です
In fact, when his own daughter
実際、自分の娘がいたとき、
by order of the father
父親の命令で
A lot of things went to the back garden
裏庭にたくさんのものが行きました
It's true that something unfortunate happened
残念なことが起こったのは事実だ
Because they met the flower spirit tree monster in the garden
庭で花精樹の怪物に出会ったから
want to rape them, seduce them
レイプしたい、誘惑したい
Luckily his big baby is very heroic
幸いなことに、彼の大きな赤ちゃんはとても勇敢です
As soon as I saw it, I got rid of these golden monsters in the garden
それを見た瞬間、私は庭にいた金色の怪物たちを追い出しました
But the question is why is the novel written like this?
しかし問題は、なぜこの小説がこのように書かれたのかということです。
when i am alone
私が一人のとき
this garden is a special place
この庭園は特別な場所です
The garden was originally a specification within a home
庭はもともと家の中にある仕様だった
An end point with the outside world
外の世界との終着点
is a very vaguely defined place
非常に曖昧に定義された場所です
in this story
この物語の中で
The garden is a place that is about to run out
庭は尽きそうな場所だ
In fact, it means that the woman wants to poke her head out.
実は、女性が頭を突き出したいという意味なのです。
That deep desire to go outside
外に出たいという深い欲求
only in the novel
小説の中だけで
This woman's desire is suppressed
この女の欲望は抑えられている
was beheaded
斬首されました
I think if you look at it this way
こうやって見るとそう思うよ
The sky and the flowers are actually from the back
空も花も本当は後ろから
It expresses the heart of women running away and pursuing
逃げる、追いかける女性の心を表現しています。
"Star World"
《明星世界》
women's novels write about their education
女性小説は教育について書いています
What about the man?
男はどうですか？
Let's take another example of a male work
男性の作品の別の例を見てみましょう
There is a very special novel in the early Qing Dynasty
清朝初期に非常に特別な小説があります
It's called "The Biography of Acting English"
その名も「演技英語伝記」
You know this is a talk
これは話だということはわかっていますよね
Very Scary Story of Father Han
ハン神父のとても怖い話
The Novel's Travels to Women
小説の女性への旅
made a very special description
非常に特別な説明をしました
A scholar once analyzed for us
かつて学者が私たちのために分析してくれた
The heroine in "The Biography of Acting in English"
『英語で演技する伝記』のヒロイン
It's Han's father named Xue Sujie
ハンさんの父親、シュエ・スージエさんです
He went out four times in his life
彼は人生で4回外出した
The experience of traveling to distant places
遠方への旅行体験
The first time was to go to Mount Tai to burn incense
初めては泰山にお焼香に行きました
second time to beijing
二度目の北京へ
The third time to Huai'an
3度目の淮安へ
The fourth time to go to Chengdu
成都に行くのは4回目
The next three times are to go
次の3回は行きます
In order to find his drunk driving husband
飲酒運転の夫を捜すために
good
良い
So
それで
Then this scholar mentioned that
するとこの学者はこう言いました
in the biographies of entertainers
芸能人の伝記の中で
The male author will constantly question
男性著者は常に質問します
And mocking a woman's ability to take care of herself outside
そして、女性が外で自分の身の回りのことをする能力を嘲笑している
want to cut vegetarian sister
ベジタリアンの妹をカットしたい
Even if he walks the avenue at home
たとえ彼が家の大通りを歩いていたとしても
make the husband kneel at his feet
夫を足元にひざまずかせる
but as soon as you go out
でも外に出るとすぐに
he is a helpless man
彼は無力な男だ
So let's take a look at this Miao Xian
それでは、この苗仙を見てみましょう
This is the 73rd chapter I want to talk about
今回は第73章についてお話したいと思います
It's just talking about burning incense on Mount Tai
泰山でお香を焚く話です
You can take a look
見てみることができます
this small
この小さい
Inside, there will be Miao Xian, who burns incense on Mount Tai.
内部では、泰山の焼香を見せる特別な集会が開催されます。
this lively situation
この賑やかな状況
This is the Jade Emperor Biography Meeting on March 3
これは3月3日の玉皇伝記会議です。
Then this Mount Tai is full of people
それからこの泰山は人でいっぱいです
impenetrable
侵入できない
and what is this dangerous
そして、これは何ですか
mixed sex in this place
この場所での混合セックス
There is no way to say that males are on one side and females are on the other.
男性が一方の側にいて、女性がもう一方の側にあると言う方法はありません。
And it's not divided into two
しかも二つに分かれてない
So regardless of gender
だから性別関係なく
Or classes are all confused
あるいはクラス全員が混乱している
such a situation
そのような状況
Only those public officials who take risks
リスクを負う公務員だけが
And those countless wives
そしてその無数の妻たち
Who will be innumerable
誰が無数にいるだろう
The wives are counted
妻も数えられる
countless wives
無数の妻
Just without a husband and without a home
ただ夫も家もない
bad women and so on
悪い女など
Then you will be paired and haunted
そうすればあなたはペアになって幽霊に取り憑かれます
There is no gentleman who is educated and reasonable
教養があり理性的な紳士はいない
Or the woman with the hand knot
あるいは手を結びつけた女性
will appear here
ここに表示されます
Then he described below
それから彼は以下のように説明しました
describe this woman woman
この女性について説明してください
Where is the danger in such a place?
そんな場所のどこに危険があるのでしょうか？
after this ridge number
この尾根番号の後に
He said, these are the vagrants
彼は言った、「これは浮浪者たちだ」
Whenever you see a woman coming
女性が来るのを見るたびに
she wants ice cream without glasses
彼女はメガネなしでアイスクリームを食べたい
pointing
ポインティング
Then there are constant comments in the mouth
その後、口の中で絶えずコメントが続きます
comment on what
何をコメントするか
commented that
とコメントしました
Oh, this man's hair is so shiny.
ああ、この人の髪はとても輝いています。
what about that person
あの人はどうですか
Yo this foot is so small
ああ、この足はとても小さいです
It's beautiful
美しい
Or that this person can't
それともこの人には無理なのか
too much powder
粉が多すぎる
face is pale
顔が青白い
He also said that the oil was not enough.
油が足りないとも言っていた。
this person is very dry
この人はとてもドライだ
I said this mouth is too big
この口は大きすぎると言った
terrible eating too much
ひどい食べ過ぎ
Well, this ass is too big, right?
まあ、このお尻は大きすぎますよね？
Didn't get up to do anything?
何かをするために起きなかったのですか？
Wait, you are constantly criticizing
待って、あなたはいつも批判しています
women on the road
路上の女性たち
what about these women
これらの女性たちはどうですか
even if they are together
たとえ一緒にいたとしても
but they
だけどあの人達
completely incapable of protecting oneself
自分を守ることが全くできない
Then I won't quote
それなら引用しないよ
because at the end of this episode
なぜならこのエピソードの終わりには
It's actually a very dire situation
実はとても悲惨な状況なんです
That means
つまり、
A bunch of wealthy people centered on Shasujie
シャスジエを中心とした富裕層の集団
When passing by this group of floating children
この浮遊児童の集団の前を通り過ぎると
because they said something wrong
彼らは何か間違ったことを言ったから
Offended this group of bad boys
この悪い奴らのグループを怒らせた
They came forward and not only called these women
彼らは、これらの女性たちに電話をかけるためだけに名乗り出たのではありません。
And stripped all their clothes
そして服をすべて脱ぎ捨てた
These women
この女性たち
The last is to be naked when going up this mountain
最後はこの山に登るときは裸になることです
It's like being insulted
まるで侮辱されてるみたいだ
as the end of this episode
このエピソードの終わりとして
then it's clear
それなら明らかだ
what about this place
この場所はどうですか
What is manifested is
現れているのは、
A Danger of Women Walking Out of Homes and into Crowds
女性が家から出て群衆の中に入る危険性
Then of course it was that era
じゃあ確かにそんな時代だったな
For this woman likes to burn incense
この女性はお香を焚くのが好きだから
pilgrimage
巡礼
A Criticism of the Habit
習慣への批判
Then it is very obvious that
それから、それは非常に明白です
A male author's warning for women traveling
女性旅行者への男性著者の警告
But whatever we just saw
しかし、私たちが今見たものは何であれ、
Lessons from Tianyuhua
天雨華からの教訓
or in the form of male authors here
またはここの男性著者の形で
This comparison game pen in English
この比較ゲームペンは英語で
He actually corresponds to
彼は実際に対応しています
Did women in society at that time really have a chance to step out of the house?
当時の社会の女性には、本当に外に出るチャンスがあったのでしょうか？
They really have the opportunity to participate in the activities of the public
彼らには公共の活動に参加する機会が本当にあります
it's a reality
それは現実です
If it's not true because some women
もしそれが真実でないなら、一部の女性は
I will go to public gardens to enjoy with my family
家族と一緒に公立庭園に行きます
If it wasn't true some women would be in the Mirror Corps
もしそれが本当じゃなかったら、何人かの女性が鏡隊に入っていただろう
Then these popular novels
それから、これらの人気のある小説
He doesn't have to express such great anxiety and resistance.
彼はそれほど大きな不安や抵抗を表現する必要はありません。
actually
実際
Whether these are real
これらは本物かどうか
To deter women they go on a tour
女性を阻止するために彼らはツアーに参加する
Denmin filed
登民提起
or dissatisfaction
または不満
Or ordinary class women who go to temples to burn incense
あるいは寺院にお焼香に行く一般階級の女性たち
or even
あるいは
Female writers like Peng's novels are in the novels
彭氏の小説に似た女性作家が小説に登場
to imagine a woman
女性を想像する
What kind of travel alone
一人旅ってどんな旅行？
I think it shows
それが示していると思います
Chinese women before modern times
近代以前の中国人女性
their timeless
彼らの時代を超えた
A Common One Desire Across Regions
地域を超えて共通する 1 つの願い
that's the desire to get out
それは外に出たいという欲求です
destination of travel
旅行の目的地
What is there to see
見どころは何ですか
It seems that it is not the point
どうやらそれは本題ではないようです
The point is to be able to go beyond the original boundaries and limitations
重要なのは、本来の境界線や制限を超えられるかどうかです
Of course, under the constraints of the social environment at that time
もちろん、当時の社会環境の制約のもとでは
Women's travel experience and women's imagination of travel
女性の旅体験と女性の旅の想像力
It makes us feel that it is actually very precious.
実はとても貴重なものだと感じさせてくれる
Okay, so during the Ming and Qing Dynasties we used this
さて、明と清の時代にはこれを使用していました
A few brief examples to introduce to you
いくつかの簡単な例を紹介します
Going further down, to the end of the Qing Dynasty and the beginning of the Ming Dynasty
さらに下って、清朝末期から明朝初期まで
Of course it's different
もちろん違います
Women's travel opportunities in this era have increased a lot
女子旅の機会がぐっと増えるこの時代
don't talk too much
あまり話さないでください
Just mentioned female students
先ほど女子学生について触れました
Sometimes there have been female students
たまに女子生徒もいた
She is going abroad to study
彼女は勉強するために海外へ行くつもりです
even study abroad
留学さえも
if only
できれば
It's very possible to go to school.
学校に行く可能性は十分にあります。
to lady
女性へ
Of course we also remember
もちろん私たちも覚えています
Liu Bichang went to Tianjin for the first time
劉碧昌氏が初めて天津へ行った
just to study
ただ勉強するために
exist
存在
When Qing Ruo
チン・ルオの場合
around the beginning of the twentieth century
20世紀初頭頃
We also finally saw
私たちもついに見ました
first step
最初の一歩
by dedicated women
献身的な女性たちによる
written by
によって書かれた
foreign mail
外国郵便
wife of a diplomat
外交官の妻
Written by Shanshini
シャンシニ著
ghost hair travel post
ゴーストヘアトラベルポスト
This is from 1903
これは1903年のものです
She later wrote another
彼女は後に別のことを書きました
It's called "Return to the Front" in 1910
1910年には「Return to the Front」と呼ばれた
out
出的
the lady
女性
Goodness, she's actually
サンシャイン彼女は実は
her post is special
彼女の投稿は特別です
So the last ten years
それでここ10年は
received
受け取った
considerable academic attention
学術的にかなりの注目を集めている
His husband is called Qin Xun
彼の夫は秦勲と呼ばれます
Is a diplomat in the late Qing Dynasty
清朝末期の外交官
went to many places to have accidents
いろんな場所に行って事故を起こした
since 1889
1889年以来
Shan Shilin followed his husband
シャン・シーリンは夫を追った
Traveled to many places
たくさんの場所に旅行しました
Shan Shilin because he is a destination
シャン・シーリンは彼が目的地だから
He took what he had seen and heard
彼は見聞きしたことをそのまま受け入れた
And his thoughts were written and mailed
そして彼の考えは書かれて郵送されました
And he writes a big point of mailing
そして彼はメールを送る上で重要なことを書いています
It is to encourage women in China at that time to speak
当時の中国の女性たちに発言を奨励するためです
imitate his spirit
彼の精神に倣う
Travel abroad to broaden your knowledge
知識を広げるために海外旅行に行く
These two parts mailed the previous part of Mandarin
これら 2 つの部分は、中国語の前の部分をメールで送信しました。
It's about his experience in Japan and Russia
それは日本とロシアでの彼の経験についてです
The second part of Homecoming is basically about countries in Western Europe
ホームカミングの第 2 部は基本的に西ヨーロッパの国々についての話です
we have to pay special attention
私たちは特別な注意を払わなければなりません
It is because of good deeds, Lin's historical environment, his career
それは善行、リンの歴史的環境、キャリアのおかげです
Wanqing is special
万清は特別です
So he writes the post with a special perspective
そこで彼は特別な観点からこの記事を書きました
what kind of perspective
どのような視点でしょうか
The first is that he is a woman
一つ目は彼が女性であるということ
He is going with his peers
彼は仲間たちと一緒に行くつもりです
Chinese woman speaking with dream
夢を語る中国人女性
The second is that he is a Chinese woman
2つ目は彼が中国人女性であるということです
The third point is
3つ目のポイントは、
He is a woman in China who is being bullied by foreign powers
彼は外国勢力からいじめを受けている中国の女性です
so you can see
それでわかります
For example, he would say this in "He You Ji"
たとえば、彼は「He You Ji」でこう言います。
He will say that our Chinese women are originally locked up
彼は、我が国の中国人女性はもともと監禁されていると言うだろう
So we never know the outside world
だから私たちは外の世界を決して知りません
Because I don't know the outside world
外の世界を知らないから
So we don't actually know ourselves
つまり、私たちは実際には自分自身を知らないのです
Because I have never seen foreign countries
外国を見たことがないので
So I don't know ours is actually called China
だから私たちの国が実際に中国と呼ばれているのか知りません
This is mutually defined
これは相互に定義されています
So he said that since I went to Japan
私が日本に行ってから彼はこう言いました
I see Japanese women are very patriotic
日本の女性はとても愛国心が強いようです
So I was also inspired
それで私も刺激を受けました
I know we women need it too
私たち女性にもそれが必要だとわかっています
patriotic this is important to the country
愛国的だ、これは国にとって重要だ
Then I also spontaneously gave birth to patriotism
そして私も自然と愛国心が芽生えた
which of course encourages his potential female readers
もちろん、これは彼の潜在的な女性読者を奨励します
Even women should be governed by national concepts
女性にも国家概念がある
Well, this is a good deed that leaves blood
まあ、これは血を流す善行だ
A more important main axis in the mail
メールにおけるより重要な主軸
Of course, he is also a woman who is full of knowledge.
もちろん知識豊富な女性でもあります。
I heard that Tolstoy was sent by him from China
トルストイは中国から彼に送られたと聞きました
So I haven't gone through a very strict inspection
それほど厳しい検査は受けていませんので、
Do not know is not true
知らないというのは真実ではない
But it is said
しかし、それは言われています
He was the first person in China to mention
彼は中国で最初に言及した人物だった
This Russian writer Tolstoy's people
ロシアの作家トルストイの人々
OK
OK
good
良い
However, this good deed is from him, although he is a woman who looks up to the original owner
しかし、この善行は元の所有者を尊敬する女性であるにもかかわらず、彼によるものです
but what do we have to say
でも何を言わなければいけないのですか
He will basically still be classified by us as a home of the Qing Dynasty
私たちは基本的に彼を清朝の故郷として引き続き分類します。
How should I put it, he is still in
彼はまだいるとどうやって言いますか
Continuing the oil change tradition we just mentioned
先ほど述べたオイル交換の伝統を継続
Why did he have the opportunity to travel abroad?
なぜ彼は海外旅行する機会があったのでしょうか?
That's because he went abroad with his husband
それは彼が夫と一緒に海外に行ったからです
So he is a follower role
つまり彼はフォロワーの役割です
He played the role of a wife in a family to go abroad
彼は海外へ行く家族の妻の役割を果たした
then maybe a little later
それから少し後かもしれない
We have a character for comparison
比較用のキャラクターがあります
This figure may be even more legendary in terms of travel
この数字は旅行の観点からはさらに伝説的なものになるかもしれません
who is this
これは誰ですか
This is Kang Youwei's second daughter
カン・ヨウウェイの次女です。
Kang Tongbi
カン・トンビ
Kang Tongbi is also a person from the end of the 19th century to the 20th century
カン・トンビも19世紀末から20世紀の人物です
He is Kang Youwei's second daughter
カン・ユーウェイの次女です。
If you have read Zhang Yihe's The Last Noble
張儀和の『最後の貴族』を読んだことのある方
maybe remember
たぶん覚えてる
Because it actually mentioned in that book
実際にその本の中で言及されていたので、
Kang Tongbi in his later years and Kang Tongbi's daughter
晩年のカン・トンビとカン・トンビの娘
That Luo Yifeng
そのルオ・イーフェン
So what kind of legendary trip did he have?
では、彼はどのような伝説的な旅をしたのでしょうか？
That was in the spring of 1902
それは1902年の春のことでした
Has the reform already failed?
改革はすでに失敗したのか？
So that Kang Youwei has gone out of town
カン・ユーウェイが町から出て行ったように
to many places
たくさんの場所へ
Finally, in 1902, Kang Youwei was here
1902年、ついに康有為がここに来た
From Southeast Asia to India
東南アジアからインドへ
Well, Kang Tongbi is not yet 20 years old at this time
さて、カン・トンビはこの時点ではまだ20歳ではありません
this is 19 years old
これは19歳です
After he found out where his father was
彼は父親の居場所を知った後、
I decided to rush to accompany my father to take care of him.
私は父の看病に急遽同行することにした。
So it is said that he is wearing men's clothes
だから男物の服を着ていると言われています
then alone
それから一人で
Go south from this Hexi Corridor
この河西回廊から南へ進みます
Then through Nanyang
その後南陽を経由して
In the end he really went to India to accompany his father Kang Youwei
結局、彼は父親のカン・ユーウェイに同行するために実際にインドに行きました。
So how do we know this?
では、どうやってこれを知ることができるのでしょうか?
Because Liang Qichao used to be here
梁啓超がここにいたから
It was mentioned in Hidden Soldiers Relief
それは隠れた兵士の救済で言及されました
Then he will talk about Kang Tong
それから彼はカントンについて話します
Last year, a person went to India to torture
昨年、ある人がインドに拷問に行きました
He is only 19 years old
彼はまだ19歳です
This is actually a little bit sexist.
これは実際には少し性差別的です。
Young age is not necessarily good job
若いから良い仕事ができるとは限らない
But he praised Kang Tongbi for being able to
しかし、彼はカン・トンビの能力を称賛した。
Blind Tao Accounting for Thousands of Miles
数千マイルを司るブラインド・タオ
It's really rich and has no dogs
本当に裕福で犬もいない
The comparison between this young and professional and the rich but without dogs
この若者とプロフェッショナルと、犬を飼っていない金持ちとの比較
It's actually quite an interesting value judgment.
実はこれは非常に興味深い価値判断です。
After telling the story
話をした後
Liang Qichao also quoted two poems by Kang Tongbi
梁啓超は康通碧の二つの詩も引用した
These are the two poems you see below
以下にある 2 つの詩です。
This is the word count of Kang Dongpil
カン・ドンピルの文字数です
He said that social mountains and rivers are formed
社会的な山河が形成されると彼は言いました。
A society is of course a social state
社会はもちろん社会国家です
It was a place name in India at that time.
当時のインドの地名です。
society city
社会都市
That's where the Buddha preached the scriptures and preached the Dharma.
そこで釈迦は経典を説き、法を説いたのです。
Sanxun
三シュン
If you don't pass, you don't pass the temple
通らなければ寺院を通らない
It is also the place where the Buddha preached
お釈迦さまが説法をされた場所でもあります
The tone below is very red
下のトーンはとても赤いです
he said bad lady rare
彼は「悪い女性は珍しい」と言った
I am the first person
私が最初の人です
it's very very confident
それはとても自信があります
very strong tone
非常に強い口調
Believe that you can do it
あなたならできると信じてください
first chinese woman
初の中国人女性
Of course, these two poems both show a very gray and red momentum.
もちろん、これらの 2 つの詩はどちらも非常に灰色と赤の勢いを示しています。
after this
この後
Kang Tongbi became a wife again in 1903
カン・トンビは1903年に再び妻となった
Actually went to America to study
実際にアメリカに留学してきました
Finally in 1909 when
ついに1909年に
from Columbia University
コロンビア大学出身
He had no way of going to the real columbia at that time
当時彼には本物のコロンビアに行く方法はなかった
He can only go to women's college
彼は女子大しか行けない
It's Bernard
バーナードです
he graduated from there
彼はそこを卒業した
He's actually a Colombian woman
実はコロンビア出身の女性です
Girls college's first graduate Asian student
女子大学初のアジア人卒業生
This is Kang Tongbi's trip
これはカン・トンビの旅です
Of course we have to say that Kang Tongbi has an extraordinary background
もちろん、カン・トンビには並外れた経歴があると言わざるを得ません。
After all, he is Kang Youwei's daughter
結局のところ、彼はカン・ユーウェイの娘です
his extraordinary family background
他的不平凡的家庭背景
In fact, it created his extraordinary experience
実際、それが彼の並外れた経験を生み出しました
But his whole travel experience
しかし、彼の旅行経験全体は、
Let's say he wants a man of his own volition
彼が自分の意志を持つ男性を望んでいるとしましょう
so far away
あまりにも遠く離れ
really thousands of miles away
本当に何千マイルも離れたところに
India to save Qing
インドが清を救う
It is also from the kind of women I just mentioned
それも先ほど述べたような女性からのものです
the desire to get out
外に出たいという欲求
a will to seek
求める意志
in fact
実際には
Kang Tongbi and Lu Bicheng
カン・トンビとルー・ビチェン
They were all born in the 1880s
彼らは全員1880年代生まれです
So they can be said to be peers
だから彼らは同類だと言える
Then they are also in the youthful temple age of life
そして彼らはまた、人生の若い神殿時代の時期にいます。
did something special
何か特別なことをしました
Kang Tongbi traveled thousands of miles to India to save
カン・トンビは命を救うために数千マイルをインドまで旅した
Wake up and study abroad
目覚めて留学しよう
And Bi Chen is about the same age
ビーチェンも同い年です
Run away from home, go to Tianjin to explore the world
家出して天津へ世界を探検する
Their travels all started
彼らの旅はすべて始まった
Some special experiences in their personal lives
私生活での特別な経験
They are also famous historical environments in the late Qing Dynasty
清朝末期の有名な歴史的環境でもあります。
create an environment for them
彼らのための環境を作る
such an opportunity
そのような機会
Of course, the end of the Qing Dynasty also began to appear
もちろん、清朝の終わりも見え始めました。
more female students
女子学生が増える
They go far and wide to read
彼らは本を読むために遠くまで出かけます
including the heroines we are familiar with
お馴染みのヒロインも含めて
Qiu Jin is also around this time
秋瑾もこの頃です
Those who went abroad to study, those who went to Japan to study
海外に留学した人、日本に留学した人
so we can see
それで私たちは見ることができます
from this time on
今回から
Chinese women have more and more opportunities to travel abroad
中国人女性は海外旅行に行く機会が増えている
so from here
だからここから
we can finally go back
やっと戻れるよ
Al Bichen's body
アル・ビチェンの遺体
And her trip to Europe and America
そして彼女のヨーロッパとアメリカへの旅行
What about Al Bichen's trip?
アル・ビチェンの旅はどうなる？
in a special historical context
特別な歴史的文脈の中で
in the late 1920s
在1920年代後期
What about this period?
この時期はどうでしょうか？
What kind of period was it?
それはどのような時代でしたか？
For Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェンの場合
His origin is China
彼の出身地は中国です
His destination is Europe and America
彼の目的地はヨーロッパとアメリカです
So the date in the 1920s
つまり、1920年代の日付です
for China
中国向け
For Europe and the United States
ヨーロッパとアメリカ向け
different meanings
さまざまな意味
The year he set out was 1926
彼が出発したのは 1926 年でした
in China
中国で
what year was that
それは何年でしたか
it was 1930
1930年のことでした
in China
中国で
what year was that
それは何年でしたか
that's exactly
それはまさに
It was the year when the Beifa Movement started
この年はベイファ運動が始まった年でした。
So
それで
where he goes
彼はどこへ行く
where is his destination
彼の目的地はどこですか
In Europe and America?
ヨーロッパとアメリカでは？
What about the 1920s?
1920年代についてはどうでしょうか？
yes
はい
Simply put, the 1920s were
簡単に言えば、1920年代は
World War I
第一次世界大戦
postwar period
戦後
Because the year of the European War
欧州戦争の年だから
1914 to 1918
1914年から1918年
then the 1920s
それから1920年代
It was after the end of the European War in 1918
それは1918年にヨーロッパ戦争が終わった後のことでした。
a special period
一段特殊的一個時期
Caught in the European War in the 1920s
1920年代にヨーロッパ戦争に巻き込まれた
Followed by the 1930s
続いて1930年代
For example, during the Great Depression in the United States
たとえば、アメリカの大恐慌のとき、
So when it comes to the European War
それで、ヨーロッパ戦争に関して言えば、
We must say this World War I
この第一次世界大戦はこう言わなければなりません
Impact on the Western world
西側世界への影響
It's indescribably huge
なんとも言えない巨大さです
I myself have actually read
私自身も実際に読んだことがあります
Because I used to study in the Department of Chinese Literature
私は中国文学科に通っていたので、
Actually read a lot of literature
実際にたくさんの文献を読んでみてください
But I'm really late
でも本当に遅刻してしまいました
Only then did I really realize that there are so many things that are
そのとき初めて、本当にたくさんのことがあったことに気づきました。
Why is it so similar to World War I?
なぜ第一次世界大戦とこれほど似ているのでしょうか？
so relevant
とても関連性のある
then
それから
What about World War I?
第一次世界大戦についてはどうですか？
It's because of this twentieth-century advance in weapons
それは 20 世紀の兵器の進歩のおかげです
so amazing
本当に素晴らしい
So it caused this
それでこれが引き起こされた
The casualties far exceed the casualty rate of wars that humans could have imagined before.
その死傷者数は、人類がこれまで想像していた戦争による死傷者数をはるかに上回っている。
Moreover, the First World War also invented a very special method of warfare
さらに、第一次世界大戦では非常に特殊な戦争方法が発明されました。
It's what you see in the picture
それは写真に見られるものです
This is Trench, the so-called Haogou Warfare
これが塹壕、いわゆる覇王戦です。
That is to say, the people on both sides have spent many months this year.
つまり、双方の人々は今年何ヶ月も過ごしたということだ。
This year, I have been preparing for the battle in Haogou for many months.
今年、私は何ヶ月もかけて覇王溝の戦いの準備をしてきました。
So for a very, very long time soldiers have to stay in this
したがって、非常に長い間、兵士たちはこの中に留まらなければなりません
then they can't get out
そうなると彼らは出られなくなる
It's really stuck inside and can't get out
本当に中に詰まっていて抜け出せない
Moreover, the sky you look up at is incomplete.
また、見上げる空は未完成です。
Looking up, you can only see a thin line of sky above Haogou
見上げると、ハオゴウの上に空の細い線しか見えません
Even days are incomplete
たとえ日が未完成でも
Then according to the conjecture of later generations?
それでは後世の推測によると？
a war experience like this
このような戦争体験
For the psychology of the soldiers who participated in the war at that time
当時の戦争に参加した兵士の心理について
had a very, very large impact
非常に非常に大きな影響を与えた
is a huge battle
大きな戦いです
window pain
窓の痛み
So
それで
and therefore in this
したがって、この中で
after the first event war
最初のイベント戦争の後
we can almost say
私たちはほぼ言うことができます
too many important
重要なことが多すぎる
this western literary work
この西洋文学作品
World War I
第一次世界大戦
caused by the psychological
心理的なものによって引き起こされる
Trauma is relevant
トラウマは関係ある
I just give a few examples
いくつか例を挙げます
Although this is already
これはもうすでにあるのですが、
History learned a very long time ago
歴史ははるか昔に学んだ
but for example
しかし、例えば
This is probably the one we are most familiar with
おそらくこれが私たちに最もよく知られているものです
Elliott
エリオット
T.S. Eliot
T.S.エリオット
Some of his most important works such as
彼の最も重要な作品のいくつかは次のとおりです。
Wasteland
荒れ地
or this
またはこれ
What is the name Hollow Man or Hollow Man?
ホロウマンまたはホロウマンという名前は何ですか?
The Hollow Man
虚ろな男
It's all from the 1920s
それはすべて 1920 年代のものです
And it's all
そしてそれがすべてです
In response to this European war
このヨーロッパ戦争に対抗して
some spirit
何かの精神
state
州
For example, this wasteland is supposed to be in 1922
たとえば、この荒野は 1922 年のことになっています。
then this
それからこれ
Hollow Man's might be a little later
ホロウマンはもう少し先になるかもしれない
Another example is the American writer Hemingway
もう一つの例は、アメリカの作家ヘミングウェイです。
his battlefield dream
彼の戦場での夢
Haruka battlefield is this
ハーモニーってこれだ
Affair to Arms
武器に関する問題
He is also talking about himself
彼は自分自身についても話しています
Some of the First World War
第一次世界大戦の一部
this traumatic experience the sense of absurdity of war and more
このトラウマ的な経験、戦争の不条理感など
That's 1929
それは 1929 年のことです
These are all works from the 1920s
これらはすべて1920年代の作品です
what they responded to
彼らが何に答えたか
All from 1914 to 1918
すべて 1914 年から 1918 年まで
this world war one
この第一次世界大戦
then these works
それからこれらの作品
they all have something in common
彼らは皆、何か共通点を持っています
have some themes
いくつかのテーマがある
they all acted
彼らは皆行動した
the generation after the war in europe
ヨーロッパの戦後世代
the psychological feeling
心理的な感情
lost hopeless
失われた絶望的な
disillusioned disillusioned
破滅 幻滅
The collapse of this value
この価値観の崩壊
everything in the world is meaningless
世界のすべては無意味だ
such a state of mind
そのような精神状態
It's just like
まるで
This is what Elliot's Holloman said
エリオットのホロマンはこう言った
He just said we were empty
彼はただ私たちが空いていると言いました
there is nothing in us
私たちの中には何もない
Even if there is something, it's just stuffed with straw
何かあっても藁を詰めただけ
like a stuff animal
動物のぬいぐるみのように
It's stuffed there, it's stuck there
そこに詰まっている、そこに詰まっている
There are straws in the head
頭にストローが入ってる
nothing
なし
And what?
そして何？
It's just like
まるで
This tangible and intangible thing is the same
有形も無形も同じです
I think this picture is very
この写真はとてもいいと思います
for me
私のため
Very meaningful expression of that feeling
その感情の非常に意味のある表現
yes
はい
like this floating shadow
この浮遊する影のように
is colorless
無色です
is powerless
無力です
You see it seems to be moving
動いているように見えるのがわかります
In fact, it has no power at all.
実際には、まったく力がありません。
there is no motion
動きがありません
so finally
それでついに
What about the end of this poem?
この詩の終わりはどうなるでしょうか？
just say
言うだけ
this is how the world ends
こうして世界は終わる
This is the way the world ends
これが世界の終わり方だ
Not with a band
バンドではない
I didn't even think about it
考えもしなかった
how did this world end
この世界はどうやって終わったのか
just use
ただ使ってください
softly
そっと
Humper is a
ハンパーは、
Wu Ye or wrong gas
Wu Ye または間違ったガス
small sound
小さな音
no sense to end with a sound
音で終わるのは意味がない
this reminds me
これは思い出します
From "Dragon Dream"
『ドラゴンドリーム』より
Yuan Xiaojie passed
袁暁傑氏が逝去
There is still a touch
まだタッチがあります
nothing
なし
But in this wild world
でもこの野生の世界では
Even Yuan Xiaojie's swollen sound
袁暁傑の膨らんだ音さえも
none
なし
So this is what the Western world calls
これが西洋世界の呼び方です
A Portrayal of the Spirit of the Lost Generation
失われた世代の精神の描写
This is the so-called spiritual wasteland
ここはいわゆる精神的な荒野です
This is the side on the window from the 1920s
こちらは1920年代の窓側です。
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
What about America in the 1920s?
1920年代のアメリカはどうだったのでしょうか？
It was a prosperous golden age
繁栄した黄金時代だった
What about other big cities in the western world?
西側世界の他の大都市はどうでしょうか？
including London and Paris
ロンドンやパリも含めて
And what about New York in the United States, and big cities like Chicago?
アメリカのニューヨークやシカゴのような大都市はどうでしょうか？
What they actually experienced was a
彼らが実際に体験したのは、
we call it crazy sales
私たちはそれをクレイジーセールスと呼んでいます
Crazy
クレイジー
era of frenzied sales
熱狂的な販売の時代
It was a very noisy time
とても騒がしい時代でした
in this era
この時代に
There are some social and cultural peculiarities in the 2000s
2000年代にはいくつかの社会的および文化的特殊性があります
For example, if we're going to talk about art
たとえば、アートについて話そうとすると、
It is an era of so-called Art Deco
いわゆるアールデコの時代です
Features of Art Deco
アールデコの特徴
For example, as you can see in the picture in the middle
たとえば、真ん中の写真にあるように、
there are many colors
たくさんの色があります
There are many geometric lines
幾何学的な線がたくさんある
influenced by industrial civilization
産業文明の影響を受けて
So those more mechanical designs that appeared
それで、より機械的なデザインが登場しました
You can see it on the clothes
服の上からでもわかります
The hat worn by the woman in the lower left corner
左下の女性がかぶっている帽子
It's what you want to describe a woman as a smoker
女性を喫煙者と表現したいのはこういうことだ
This is the smoke room girl
こちらは喫煙室の女の子です
It's also the age of movies
映画の時代でもある
Choplin was active in that era
チョップリンはこの時代に活躍した
An era when Hollywood movies first flourished
ハリウッド映画が隆盛を極めた時代
At the same time it is Jazz Age
同時にジャズエイジでもある
it's time for jazz month
ジャズ月間の時期が来ました
jazz month useful
役に立つジャズ月間
Yes, there are five
はい、5つあります
Then he also includes this
それから彼はこれも含めます
An Era of Nightclub Nightlife
ナイトクラブのナイトライフの時代
then at the same time
それから同時に
He is also the one seen in the upper left corner
左上隅に見えるのも彼です
between men and women
男と女の間
one era
ある時代
Let's take a look at some sounds
いくつかの音を見てみましょう
I can feel the feeling of that era
あの時代の気分が伝わってきます
Please bear with me
ご了承ください
advertise
宣伝する
four seconds will continue at last
ついに4秒続く
this is
これは
Some Foreshadowings of Paris in the 1920s
1920年代のパリを予感させるいくつかのヒント
OK, let's see this
はい、これを見てみましょう
Okay, what about the nightlife we ​​just mentioned, let's take a look
さて、それでは先ほど述べたナイトライフについてはどうでしょうか、見てみましょう
How does Jazz Age behave in this NightCog?
Jazz Age はこの NightCog でどのように動作しますか?
This is the sound of the 20th-century Jazz Age.
これは20世紀のジャズエイジのサウンドです。
If you want to see more colourful images of the 20th-century,
20世紀のカラフルなイメージをもっと見たい場合は、
I suggest you to go back to the movies you've watched recently.
最近見た映画に戻ってみることをお勧めします。
The new film, The Big Red Cross, was released in 2020.
新作映画『大赤十字』は2020年に公開された。
Of course, this is basically the poster of the movie.
もちろん、これは映画のポスターです。
You can see the background of it.
その背景が見えてきます。
It is a design of Art Deco
アールデコ調のデザインです
The entire font is characteristic of that era
フォント全体がその時代の特徴です
The one below is actually his still photo I posted.
下の写真は実際に私が投稿した彼の静止写真です。
We can also be very clear in the stills
静止画でも非常に鮮明に撮影できます
Just see his whole color woman image
彼の全身カラーの女性の画像を見てください
life inside the picture inside
絵の中の人生
The kind that can be conveyed in this picture
この写真で伝わるのは
decadent indulgence very sensual
退廃的な耽溺、非常に官能的
Then it is actually a world with a very dead, floating atmosphere.
すると、実はそこは非常に死んだ、浮遊した雰囲気を持った世界なのです。
And behind him, there is actually an absurd person in the heart.
そして彼の背後には、実は心の中にとんでもない人物がいる。
self-imposed exile
最も洗練された自己亡命
There is also a mental state that breaks with tradition
伝統を打ち破る精神状態もある
This is the background of the 1920s when Lu Bicheng traveled to Europe and America
これはルー・ビチェンがヨーロッパとアメリカを旅行した1920年代の背景です
Such a prosperous and smooth scene is not the same as that of modern people.
このような豊かで順風満帆な光景は、現代人のそれと同じではありません。
Xinning's barren thorns jointly built the Western European and American world in the 1920s
新寧の不毛の棘が 1920 年代に西ヨーロッパとアメリカの世界を共同で構築した
Well, at least in the United States until this and that Wall Street Crash in 1929
まあ、少なくとも米国では、1929 年のあのウォール街大暴落までは
That's why such a world collapsed
だからそんな世界は崩壊した
Then after that, it will be the long-term Great Depression era of the American economy.
そしてその後、アメリカ経済は長期にわたる大恐慌の時代となる。
So, when Lu Micheng went to Europe and America to roam
それで、ルー・ミチェンがヨーロッパとアメリカに放浪に行ったとき、
Most of the time he is in such a situation
ほとんどの場合、彼はそのような状況にあります
This is a case of his destination
これは彼の目的地での事例です
Then I think the reason why Lu Bicheng is in his travel notes
では、ルー・ビチェンが旅行記に登場する理由は次のとおりだと思います。
Often expresses a very melancholy mood
非常に憂鬱な気分を表現することが多い
There is also a feeling of boredom and vulgarity.
退屈さと下品さの感覚もあります。
On the other hand, he has a kind of sincerity for luxury, beauty, luxury, splendor, etc.
その一方で、贅沢、美しさ、豪華さ、素晴らしさなどに対してはある種の誠実さを持っています。
These two emotions exist at the same time
この二つの感情は同時に存在する
Well, I think it's not just about his own personal
まあ、それは彼自身の個人的な問題だけではないと思います
For example, his family is considered unfortunate.
たとえば、彼の家族は不幸だと考えられています。
For example, his health is obviously not good.
たとえば、彼の健康状態は明らかに良くありません。
He always thinks he's dying
彼はいつも自分が死ぬと思っている
wait for such factors
そういった要因を待つ
In fact, it also has something to do with the general environment of the place he visited.
実際、それは彼が訪れた場所の一般的な環境とも関係があります。
are closely related
密接に関係している
The overall atmosphere is just like his soul
全体的な雰囲気はまさに彼の魂のようです
What about the feeling?
気持ちはどうでしょうか？
I feel empathy
共感を覚えます
are echoes of each other
お互いのエコーです
So let's read this now
それでは、今すぐこれを読んでみましょう
What about Lu Bicheng's European and American Man You Road?
ルー・ビチェンの『欧米人遊路』はどうですか？
I think our readers at the same time as him
私たちの読者も彼と同じだと思います
It's like getting a little bit of a bargain
ちょっとしたお買い得品をゲットしたような気分です
Because we are looking at that time from modern times
現代から当時を見ているから
we can see
見える
We can see the feeling of that whole era from behind
あの時代の雰囲気を後ろから見ると
And what about Lu Bicheng and his contemporary readers?
そして、ルー・ビチェンと彼の現代の読者はどうなるでしょうか？
It may not feel like this
こんな感じではないかもしれない
to feel his emotions
彼の感情を感じるために
This relationship with his environment
彼の環境とのこの関係
So this post-construction name is still better.
だから、この建設後の名前の方がまだ良いです。
well then
じゃあ
Because Chinese women sold oil alone in Europe and America in the 1920s
1920年代に中国人女性がヨーロッパやアメリカで石油を単独で販売していたため
except of her own will
彼女自身の意志以外に
What other factors can support her?
彼女をサポートできる他の要因は何でしょうか?
Then I have to pull Lu Bicheng back to
それから私はルー・ビチェンを引き戻さなければなりません
Consider it within the context of her own era
彼女自身の時代の文脈で考えてみましょう
Then in this China
それからこの中国では
In fact, as early as the 1910s in magazines
実際、1910年代にはすでに雑誌で
Mailing is a very important column
メール送信は非常に重要な項目です
Many magazines will have a mailing column
多くの雑誌にはメールコラムがあります
Everyone likes to watch other people travel and you know why
誰もが他の人が旅行するのを見るのが好きです、そしてあなたはその理由を知っています
What about magazines, in fact, they are often read in women's mail
雑誌はどうですか、実は女性向けメールでよく見かけます。
in particular
特に
I like looking at the lights
ライトを見るのが好きです
schoolgirl mail
女子高生メール
schoolgirl's work
女子高生の仕事
Then of course the female student won't go anywhere far with his post
それならもちろん、女子学生は自分のポストをどこにも行かないでしょう
For example, when we were young, we all wrote Yangmingshan mail, right?
たとえば、私たちが若い頃、陽明山メールを書きましたよね？
almost like that
ほぼその通り
But others are a postal
ただし他は郵便
He will become a school for girls
彼は女子校になるだろう
Composition education is an important part of his education.
作曲教育は彼の教育の重要な部分です。
This fact itself represents
この事実自体が表しています
From the relationship with women to the previous generation
女性関係から先代まで
is completely different
全く違います
We'll see all kinds of women's mailings in magazines
雑誌にはあらゆる種類の女性向けメールが掲載されます
Or it includes women's feelings after going out for a swim
あるいは、海水浴に行った後の女性の気持ちも含まれます
Let's say I see a record that is
次のレコードを見たとしましょう。
A first generation Liu Mei's schoolgirl
初代リウ・メイの女学生。
He wrote that when he returned to China and disembarked
彼は中国に戻って下船したときにこう書いた。
Set foot on the land of Shanghai, that mess
上海の地を踏め、あの混沌
put him down
彼を降ろす
This in turn is a cultural fine-fork sense
これはひいては、優れたフォークセンスの文化です
will happen
起こります
Women's Mail of the 1910s in This Era
1910年代の女性向けメールを今の時代に
In fact, some of them are very good and quite unique.
実際、それらの中には非常に優れた、非常にユニークなものもあります。
For example, the author of this article is called Ji Zonglan
たとえば、この記事の著者は Ji Zonglan と呼ばれます。
What you guys see here is him on
ここに見えるのは彼です
Volume 11 of the Women's Magazine
女性誌Vol.11
That is, December 1915
つまり、1915 年 12 月
December
12月
A mailing by me is called "Yue Shan Ji"
私からのメールは「ユエ・シャン・ジ」と呼ばれています
what about this article
この記事はどうですか
In fact, the structure is very complete
実際、構造は非常に完成度が高い
He talked about this natural landscape
彼はこの自然の風景について話しました
He spoke of what he observed as a problem with social prestige
彼は社会的威信に関わる問題として観察したことについて語った
Then he also mentioned some of his historical feelings in Guanlaoyu
それから彼は関老嶼の歴史的感情についても言及しました。
So what can we say about this woman's insight?
それでは、この女性の洞察力について何が言えるでしょうか?
actually quite remarkable
実際かなり注目に値する
So at the end of this article
そこでこの記事の最後に
what about the author
著者はどうですか
Ji Zonglan said very confidently
季宗蘭氏は自信満々にこう言った。
what about my trip
私の旅行はどうですか
Learn from it
から学びます
learn while traveling
旅行中に学ぶ
this is a purposeful trip
これは目的のある旅行です
I'm not like those boring people in Shanghai, am I?
私は上海の退屈な人たちとは違うんですよね？
I only run horses every day.
毎日馬を走らせるだけです。
watch a play what?
演劇を観て何？
steamed and sea
蒸し物と海
those who are useless
役に立たない人たち
i am useful
私は役に立ちます
My study and travel are combined
勉強と旅行を組み合わせています
This is Ji Zonglan
季宗蘭です
he is very firm
彼はとてもしっかりしている
learn from travel
旅行から学ぶ
Inquiry equates travel with knowledge
探求は旅と知識を意味します
So who is Ji Zonglan?
それで、季宗蘭とは誰ですか？
Ji Zonglan was a female educator in the early Ming Dynasty
季宗蘭は明朝初期の女性教育者でした。
This is the same as Lu Bicheng's early identification
これはルー・ビチェンの初期の特定と同じです
So special is Ji Zonglan
季宗蘭はとても特別です
He actually has another post
実は彼には別の役職がある
It's called Guilin Travel Notes
その名も「桂林旅行記」
It was also published in the same magazine
同誌にも掲載されました
It's volume four, number six, of women's magazines.
女性誌の第4巻第6号です。
That is, in June 1918
つまり、1918年6月に
Then this post
それからこの投稿
later renamed
後に名前が変更されました
Renamed as Guilin Post
桂林郵便局に改名
Is received ancient and modern mail from the inside
古今の郵便物を内部から受信
His writing is the same as the past and present
彼の文章は昔も今も同じだ
Mailing with the Eight Great Masters of the Tang and Song Dynasties
唐宋の八大巨匠とのメール
Put it together, rise up, sit up
組み立てて、立ち上がって、座って
good
良い
then we can see something like this
そうすると、次のようなものが表示されます
We take this post by Ji Zonglan as a representative
季宗蘭氏を代表として就任
This category of this early twentieth century woman's mailing
20世紀初頭の女性のメールのこのカテゴリ
they did it on purpose
彼らは故意にそれをした
Demonstrate knowledge, study, enlightenment, view of current affairs, view of history, etc.
知識、学問、啓蒙、時事観、歴史観などを証明する。
Positive going with this big one
この大きなもので前向きに進んでいます
Some viewpoints corresponding to the trend
トレンドに応じたいくつかの視点
a positive spirit
ポジティブな精神
We just talked about the characteristics of this era in the 1920s
1920 年代というこの時代の特徴についてお話しました。
So what about events in Europe and America?
では、ヨーロッパやアメリカでの出来事はどうでしょうか？
The 1920s happened to be the tourism industry
1920 年代は観光産業の時代でした
A period of particularly developed leaps and bounds
特に飛躍的に発展した時代
In this day and age, I was supposed to travel abroad
このご時世、海外旅行に行くはずだった
Not so common yet, in the 20's
20代ではまだそれほど一般的ではありません
more and more popular
ますます人気が高まっています
What about Lubi City's roaming?
ルビシティのローミングはどうですか？
It can also be said that it is a victory
勝利とも言える
Just came across the tourism industry
観光業界に出会ったばかり
The booming period of international tourism
国際観光ブームの時代
we can see
見える
What about Lu Bicheng after he arrived in Europe and America?
ヨーロッパとアメリカに到着したルー・ビチェンはどうなりましたか？
Along the way, I took, for example, this transoceanic ship.
途中、たとえばこの大洋横断船に乗りました。
He's even been on a plane
彼は飛行機にも乗ったことがある
Then every time he arrives
それから彼が到着するたびに
Where did the travel agency go to book tickets?
旅行代理店はチケットを予約するためにどこに行きましたか?
to send luggage
荷物を届けなければなりません
accept luggage
荷物を受け取る
or exchange money
またはお金を両替する
he will use
彼は使うでしょう
modern tourism services
現代の観光サービス
for example
例えば
For example, what is this Kirk?
たとえば、このカークは何ですか？
This Thomas Cook
このトーマス・クック
or American Express
またはアメリカン・エキスプレス
We still use this travel service
私たちは今でもこの旅行サービスを利用しています
At that time, Lu Bi's achievements were already in use
この時すでに呂備の功績は活かされていた
And he highly recommends
そして彼は強く勧めます
If you want to travel
旅行したいなら
Be sure to use these travel industry services
旅行業界のサービスをぜひご利用ください
These make his journey
これらが彼の旅を作る
even traveling alone
一人旅でも
Traveling alone is also convenient
一人旅も便利です
Then the same period
それから同時期に
how is the situation in china
中国の状況はどうですか
For the first time in Lu Bicheng
魯碧城で初めて
Announced in the newspaper that he was going to start
入社することが新聞で発表されました
When traveling in Europe and America
ヨーロッパやアメリカを旅行するとき
he mentioned
彼は言及した
My post
私の投稿
after writing it out
書き出した後
can be the guide of the people
人々の導き手になることができる
It can be used as a reference for Chinese people to go abroad
中国人が海外に行く際の参考になる
Since he said so
彼がそう言ったから
Of course, it was expected that Chinese people at that time would also have the opportunity to travel abroad like him.
もちろん、当時の中国人も彼のように海外旅行に行く機会があると予想されていた。
Well in fact it is
まあ実際そうなんですが
since 1927
1927年以来
Shanghai Commercial Savings Bank they set up a travel department
上海商業貯蓄銀行は旅行部門を設立しました
started publishing a magazine called a travel magazine
旅行雑誌という雑誌を発行し始めた
This is his release
これが彼のリリースです
This travel magazine is actually published by him
この旅行雑誌は実際に彼が発行したものです
very long release period
非常に長いリリース期間
Published from 1927 until 1954
1927 年から 1954 年まで出版
This travel magazine is mainly for Chinese readers
この旅行雑誌は主に中国人読者を対象としています
Provide various domestic and foreign travel information
国内・海外の様々な旅行情報をご提供します
first magazine
最初の雑誌
Of course, it is a product of the consumer culture in Shanghai in the 1920s
もちろん、1920年代の上海の消費文化の産物です。
His founder, Chen Guangfu, must be very sharp
彼の創始者である陳光福氏は非常に鋭い人物に違いありません
discover to travel
旅行するために発見する
will be
になるだろう
It will be a promising industry in the future
将来有望な業界です
so he
彼は
not only
だけでなく
Founded a travel magazine
旅行雑誌を創刊
And also formally applied for the establishment of China Travel Agency
そして中国旅行代理店の設立も正式に申請
that is Chinese
それは中国人です
Really the first travel agency in China
本当に中国初の旅行会社
It can be seen that in modern China
現代中国でもそれがわかる
The development of tourism in the 1920s
1920年代の観光業の発展
In fact, it did not fall behind the West
実際、それは西側諸国に遅れをとっていませんでした。
We can take a look at this is a travel advertisement in a travel magazine
これは旅行雑誌の旅行広告です。
they have routes to europe
彼らはヨーロッパへのルートを持っています
There are airlines to the United States, and all countries in the world fly
アメリカ行きの航空会社があり、世界中の国が飛んでいます
He can help you arrange luxury trains, tours, etc.
豪華列車やツアーなどの手配をお手伝いします。
So I believe that it is a good idea for readers
読者にとっては良いアイデアだと思います
Just sit at home and watch
ただ家で座って見てください
is also very attractive
もとても魅力的です
I think the look of the travel magazine has witnessed
旅行雑誌の見た目で目撃したと思います
A development of Chinese tourism
中国人観光業の発展
In the 18th year of the Republic of China, that is, in 1929
中華民国18年、つまり1929年
When Bicheng was still roaming
備城がまだ放浪していた頃
What about this travel magazine in three volumes and six issues?
3 巻 6 号あるこの旅行雑誌はどうでしょうか?
i found one
一つ見つけました
very interesting material
非常に興味深い資料
then it is
それならそうです
travel magazine announced
旅行雑誌が発表されました
they sponsor a
彼らはスポンサーになっています
young female
若い女性
do it once
進行一次
long trip
長旅
So this is what the editor of this magazine said
この雑誌の編集者はこう言いました
Please look at the framed part in the lower left corner
左下の枠部分をご覧ください。
He said that our local article in this issue is called
彼は、今号の私たちの地元の記事はこう呼ばれていると言いました。
Nishigata Diary Middle Small Frame Nishigata Diary
西形日記中間小框西形日記
The author is Chen Fangcheng
著者は陳方成氏です。
This lady is entertained by our company
この女性は当社に接待されています
as a lonely woman
孤独な女性として
Crossing the East Yellow Sea from the north of Shanghai
上海の北から東黄海を渡る
To the three eastern provinces
東三省へ
It's so far from the Trans-Siberian Railway
シベリア鉄道からは遠い
And drive
そしてドライブ
of France
フランスの
Paris
パリ
Long March tens of thousands of miles
数万マイルの長征
Dozens of days
数十日
Why is his brave and adventurous spirit so vivid?
なぜ彼の勇敢で冒険心はこれほど鮮やかなのでしょうか？
middle school grievances
中学生の不満
those who have heard the news
そのニュースを聞いて同じ心を持った人たち
Cry, Chinese women, come, come together
泣け、中国人女性よ、来い、集まれ
join this tour
このツアーに参加する
Okay, so who is Chen Fangchen?
さて、チェン・ファンチェンとは誰ですか？
Chen Fangchen is the one in the photo
写真はチェン・ファンチェンさんです
He is Chen Xuezhao
彼は陳学昭です
Chen Xuezhao was a quite famous female writer during the May 4th period
陳雪照は五四時代の非常に有名な女性作家でした。
Of course she is much younger than this Lu Bicheng
もちろん、彼女はこのルー・ビチェンよりもはるかに若いです
I must also say that no matter in terms of cultural identity
文化的アイデンティティの観点からは関係ないとも言わなければなりません
Or political identity
あるいは政治的アイデンティティ
She also took a completely different path from Lu Bicheng.
彼女はまた、ルー・ビチェンとはまったく異なる道を歩みました。
she is a journalism writer
彼女はジャーナリズムライターです
also a communist
共産主義者でもある
In the end, she should have become a CPPCC member or something.
結局、彼女は政協委員か何かになるべきだった。
So her life is very different from that of Lu Bicheng.
したがって、彼女の人生はルー・ビチェンの人生とは大きく異なります。
Anyway, this travel magazine at the time
それにしても、当時のこの旅行雑誌
would think of sponsoring a woman
女性のスポンサーになることを考えるだろう
He knew it was a schoolgirl with curly hair
彼はそれが巻き毛の女子高生であることを知っていた
He's apparently in France
どうやらフランスにいるらしい
Then after returning to China
そして中国に帰国後
Accepted the sponsorship of this trip again
今回も旅行の協賛を引き受けました
took a rather roundabout one
かなり回り道をした
a road
一個路
In fact, he could just go straight to
実際、彼はまっすぐに行くことができました
Just like Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェンみたいに
Can you just go to France?
そのままフランスに行ってもいいですか？
But he has to walk
でも彼は歩かなければならない
run to siberia
シベリアへ走る
This is definitely a travel agency
ここは間違いなく旅行代理店です
A set itinerary for him
彼のための決まった旅程
It is a specially designed itinerary
特別に企画された旅程です
In order to highlight this journey
この旅を輝かせるために
is a feat
偉業です
is a long march
長い行進です
So it's about this woman
それからこの女性のことです
alone
1人
Being able to take risks like pan male spirit
パンマン精神のようにリスクを取れること
Then of course his request
それからもちろん彼のリクエスト
is a progressive
進歩的です
independent brave revolutionary women
独立した勇敢な革命家の女性
then obviously this
それから明らかにこれ
Chen Xuezhao represents the brave
陳学照は勇敢な人物を代表する
What about the image of a woman?
女性のイメージはどうでしょうか？
Mixiang Yuyi
ミシアン・ユイ
with a feather on the head
頭に羽が生えている
wearing tightly embroidered clothes
しっかりと刺繍が入った服を着ている
Lu Bicheng's
ルー・ビチェンさん
The image of an oil seller is completely different
石油売りのイメージが全く違います
But we can know from this example
しかし、この例からわかるのは、
also as a lonely
孤独者としても
woman traveling alone
一人旅の女性
In fact, Lu Bicheng didn't punish his companions either.
実際、魯碧成は仲間を罰しませんでした。
Chen Xuezhao is a living example
陳雪照は生きた例です
then indeed like this
それから本当にこのように
A person is able to board the journey by himself
人は一人で旅に乗ることができる
Maybe it really is a woman of the twentieth century
もしかしたら本当に20世紀の女性なのかもしれない
twentieth century women
20世紀の女性たち
A new option when traveling
旅の新たな選択肢
This is really a woman from the previous generation
これはまさに先代の女性です
no way to enjoy
楽しむ方法がない
Women's Lives in the Late Qing and Early Ming Dynasties
清末から明初期の女性の生活
It actually happened
それは実際に起こりました
many, many new possibilities
たくさんの、たくさんの新しい可能性
There are so many excellent women
優秀な女性がたくさんいます
Lu Bicheng can be said to belong to this generation
ルー・ビチェンはこの世代に属すると言えます。
Just one of the great women
偉大な女性の一人にすぎません
But if we talk about travel
でも旅行の話をすると
Then their trip to Europe and America
その後ヨーロッパとアメリカへの旅
In fact, his characteristics
実は彼の特徴は、
It's not that he's traveled more than others
彼が他の人よりもたくさん旅行してきたというわけではない
go farther than others
他の人よりも遠くへ行く
Or his Jianwen is more broadcast than others
あるいは、彼の建文は他のものよりも多く放送されています
But I think he especially emphasized
しかし、彼は特に強調していたと思います
Neither learning nor adventure
学びでも冒険でもない
It's the level of roaming
ローミングのレベルです
His travel notes are called European and American Wandering Road
彼の旅行記は「ヨーロッパとアメリカの放浪の道」と呼ばれています
This trip from 1926
1926 年のこの旅行
He doesn't want to be a citizen
彼は国民になりたくない
do not want to study
勉強したくない
I don't want to think about saving the country every year
毎年国を救うなんて考えたくない
The few examples we gave earlier
先ほど挙げたいくつかの例
have a purpose
目的がある
But Lu Bicheng's roaming
しかし、ルー・ビチェンはさまよっている
roaming
ローミング
no purpose
目的がない
I think at this level
このレベルだと思う
he really read a bar
彼は本当にバーを読んだ
that belonged outside the entire tourism discourse of the time
それは当時の観光論全体の枠外に属していた
But maybe that's why
でもたぶんそれが理由
When we read Lu Bicheng's travel notes today
今日、Lu Bicheng の旅行記を読んだとき
We also often feel his intention to read Chuang
荘氏を読みたいという彼の意図もよく感じられます。
deodorize
消臭する
Then the last period of time, I want to come
それでは最後の期間、行きたいと思います
Let me share with you where Lu Bichen is
ルー・ビチェンがどこにいるのか教えてください
what is written in the mail
メールには何が書いてあるのか
So
それで
Traveling in Europe and America is basically written following his travel footprints
ヨーロッパとアメリカの旅は基本的に彼の旅の足跡をたどって書かれています
It started from San Francisco in the west of the United States
アメリカ西部のサンフランシスコから始まりました
then to chicago
それからシカゴへ
then to new york
それからニューヨークへ
took a boat across the Atlantic
ボートで大西洋を渡った
to Paris, France
フランス、パリへ
Then take the train
それから電車に乗ります
go to switzerland
スイスに行く
Arrived in Geneva to take over
引き継ぎのためジュネーブに到着
Huguangshan Temple
湖広山寺
And then to Milan, Italy
その後イタリア・ミラノへ
Ancient Lawrence
古代のロレンス
Rome
ローマ
then back to paris
それからパリに戻ります
Then from Paris through Switzerland and Italy
その後パリからスイス、イタリアを経由して
What is this Napoleon?
このナポレオンは何ですか？
Pompeii, Venice
ポンペイ、ヴェネツィア
In the end it was there
結局そこにあったんだよ
he took the plane
彼は飛行機に乗った
For the first time in his life, he took a plane
彼は生まれて初めて飛行機に乗りました
Arrived in Australia
オーストラリアに到着しました
vienna
ウィーン
Then take the train
それから電車に乗ります
to berlin
ベルリンへ
After returning to Paris?
パリに戻ってからは？
exist
存在
this
これ
cross the sea
渡海
arrive
到着
go to london
ロンドンに行く
Then to Paris, then to Switzerland
それからパリへ、そしてスイスへ
Finally settled down in Switzerland
ついにスイスに定住しました
So in the beginning he made Paris his center
それで最初はパリを中心に据えた
But in the end he chose to settle in Switzerland
しかし最終的に彼はスイスに定住することを選択した
Of course this journey is very complicated
もちろんこの旅はとても複雑です
But even from our perspective today,
しかし、今日の私たちの視点から見ても、
We also have to say it's a luxury trip
贅沢な旅とも言えますね
is a dream trip
夢の旅です
at the beginning of the journey
旅の始まりに
We just said he started in San Francisco
彼はサンフランシスコから始めたと言ったばかりです
Well, Journey Bicheng actually described it at the very beginning
さて、Journey Bichengは実際に最初にそれについて説明しました
Before he left for Europe from San Francisco
彼がサンフランシスコからヨーロッパに出発する前に
he used to visit hollywood
彼はよくハリウッドを訪れていた
Whether he writes about Hollywood
彼はハリウッドについて書いているかどうか
Or he can write about Paris or London later.
あるいは、後でパリやロンドンについて書くこともできます。
All revealed his love for the city's prosperity
誰もが街の繁栄に対する彼の愛を明らかにした
a yearning and nature
憧れと自然
Well, we just mentioned
さて、先ほども言いましたが、
What about America in the 1920s?
1920年代のアメリカはどうだったのでしょうか？
Is the most developed era of the film industry
映画産業が最も発展した時代
Then the halo of the star is of course the moment of this holy collection
そして、星の後光はもちろん、この神聖なコレクションの瞬間です
So, Lu Bicheng wants to go to Hollywood for a tour?
ルー・ビチェンはハリウッドにツアーに行きたいと考えている
In fact, it is also a matter of course
実はそれも当然のことなのですが、
So what happens when he gets to Hollywood?
それで、彼がハリウッドに行ったら何が起こるでしょうか？
In particular, he wrote that he went to visit the star's residence
特にスターの邸宅を訪問したと書いている。
He used very, very wonderful early words
彼はとてもとても素晴らしい初期の言葉を使っていました
To describe what he sees is not a star
彼が見ているものを説明するのはスターではない
but where the stars live
でも星が住んでいる場所
But the interesting thing is
しかし、興味深いのは
Just like when we read "A Dream of Red Mansions"
『紅楼夢』を読んだときのように
we would say that one has one's residence
人は自分の住居を持っていると言うでしょう
Where does Lin Daiyu live?
林大宇はどこに住んでいますか?
It must be regarded as the movie of Sensenlong
センセンロングの映画とみなすべき
have pigs
豚がいる
So what about the place where Xiubao lives?
では、秀宝が住んでいる場所はどうなるのでしょうか？
Bili Teng Luo
ビリ・テン・ルオ
There is a cold feeling
冷たい感触がある
So where does Jia Baoyu live?
それで、Jia Baoyuはどこに住んでいますか？
it has to be this
これでなければなりません
There is a daughter's smell, a powdery smell
女の子っぽい匂い、パウダリーな匂いがある
Then take Lin Long Baoge and so on
次に、Lin Long Baogeなどを受け取ります。
Where do you live?
どこに住んでいますか？
Just like this person's temperament, temperament
この人の気質と同じだ
Even fate is linked together
運命さえも繋がっている
When visiting the homes of Hollywood superstars
ハリウッドのスーパースターの家を訪問するとき
He played the reading method of Dream of Red Mansions
彼は紅楼夢の朗読法を演奏した
Compare the atmosphere of this superstar's house with the image of this star
このスーパースターの家の雰囲気とこのスターの画像を比較してください
His status in Hollywood and so on made a link
ハリウッドなどでの彼の地位がリンクした
So let's take an example
それでは例を挙げてみましょう
He seemed to be interested in this at the time
当時彼はこれに興味を持っていたようです
In fact, the Hollywood star who died not long ago
実は、つい最近亡くなったハリウッドの大スター
It is a special favorite of Panentino's relatives and friends
パネンティーノの親戚や友人の特別なお気に入りです。
Although I think he said with a little false confidence
彼は少し間違った自信を持って言ったと思うが
Oops, Panentino isn't very good looking.
おっと、パネンティーノはあまり格好良くありません。
Italian men are much prettier than him
イタリア人男性は彼よりもずっと美しい
But in fact he is very interested in Panentino
しかし実際には彼はパネンティーノに非常に興味を持っている
Then he specifically mentions
それから彼は具体的に言及します
When he visited the former residence of Panentino
パネンティーノの旧邸を訪れたとき
found the atmosphere of this place very heavy
この場所の雰囲気がとても重いと感じた
vocal range sound forest
音域音森
No wonder the owner of this house can't live long
この家の主人が長生きできなかったのも不思議ではない
but he
でも彼は
He also paid special attention to the original center of the house
彼はまた、家の元の中心に特別な注意を払いました
There are all kinds of exotic flowers and plants
さまざまな種類のエキゾチックな花や植物があります
There is a special flower
特別な花があります
He said there was an unknown
彼は未知のことがあると言いました
a strange plant
奇妙な植物
just be a flower
ただの花になってください
Then the color is very, very gorgeous
それから、色がとてもとても綺麗です
And this flower is very big
そしてこの花はとても大きいです
But because it's too big
でも大きすぎるから
this gold can't hold it
この金はそれを保持できない
so it hangs down
だから垂れ下がる
relying on the sidelines
傍観者に頼って
Then he used a very interesting description to say
それから彼は非常に興味深い説明を使ってこう言いました
The bully of endless flowers
終わりのない花のいじめっ子
i think i don't need to say more
これ以上言う必要はないと思います
Then what he describes is, on the surface, a strange flower
すると彼が説明するのは、表面的には奇妙な花です
In fact, it is equivalent to
実際、それは次と同等です
Handsome, elegant, a symbiosis of Panentino's idol
ハンサム、エレガント、パネンティーノのアイドルの共生
or a photo
または写真
A little photo of the heart, a reflection of the heart
心の小さな写真、心の反映
Then, Lu Bichen said
すると、ルー・ビチェンはこう言った。
Then when he sailed across the Atlantic
それから彼が大西洋を航海したとき
On the ship, I also dreamed that Panentino came to give him the name of the place.
船上では、パネンティーノが地名を教えに来たという夢も見た。
I think this can really be used as a case for psychoanalysis
これは本当に精神分析の事例として使えると思う
Then we might as well take a look with you
それなら、一緒に見てみましょう
Mulan Ruji in Paris mentioned in the travel notes
旅行記に記されたパリのムーラン・ルジ
What is this place called Mulan Ruji?
木蘭如地というこの場所は何ですか？
can you guess
推測できますか
Mulan Ruji
ムーラン・ルジ
Mulan Ruji, Mulan's Nurse
ムーラン・ルジ、ムーランの看護師
It is the Hongmofang as we know it today.
それが今日私たちが知っているホンモファンです。
Well, Lu Bichen described in great detail
さて、ルー・ビチェンは非常に詳細に説明しました
The performance he saw in this Red Ink Workshop
今回のレッドインクワークショップで彼が見たパフォーマンス
may wish to read his text
彼の文章を読みたいかもしれない
Well, this is the very early text of the day
さて、これがその日の最初のテキストです
He said that I will not read this long-term relationship
彼は、私がこの長期的な関係を読むつもりはないと言った
Basically, feel it
基本的には感じてください
Just look at the words and condemnation here.
ここでの言葉と非難を見てください。
He's saying the show is the actors on stage
彼はショーは舞台上の俳優だと言っている
All stars performing
オールスターパフォーマンス
There's Mars, there's Venus, there's the moon, whatever.
火星も金星も月も何でもあります。
Everyone is dressed like a star in the sky
誰もが空の星のように着飾っています
very beautiful
非常に美しい
His description is of course a kind of shaping is a very strong and disgusting feeling
彼の描写はもちろんある種の造形であり、非常に強くて嫌な感じです
His writing is a performance in itself
彼の文章はそれ自体がパフォーマンスである
Just like Mulan Ruji's performance on the stage is as exquisite
ムーラン・ルジのステージ上のパフォーマンスも同様に絶妙です
But I think we can also feel
しかし、私たちも感じることができると思います
When he wrote in such an early-established classical Chinese
彼がそのような初期に確立された古典的な中国語で書いたとき
very interesting
とても興味深い
It’s obviously a western scene, it’s a modern scene
それは明らかに西洋のシーンです、それは現代のシーンです
Written by him in such classical Chinese
彼によって古典中国語で書かれた
Why do you seem to be eavesdropping
どうして盗み聞きしているようだ
Has it become the advanced of Chinese classical imagination?
それは中国の古典的な想像力の進歩になったのだろうか？
Do you feel that way?
そう感じますか？
Then, Lu Bicheng's writing in classical Chinese
次に、ルー・ビチェンの古典的な中国語の文章
An example of transforming Western modernity into Chinese tradition
西洋の近代性を中国の伝統に変換した例
In fact, there are many
実際にはたくさんあります
Let's say he writes about what the symbols of Hollywood are
彼がハリウッドのシンボルとは何かについて書いたとします。
Is it just the words on the mountain?
山上の言葉だけでしょうか？
That word Hollywood
ハリウッドという言葉
But it was like this
でもこんな感じでした
he described what he saw
彼は自分が見たものを説明した
He said
彼は言った
On the one hand, I saw this Cuifeng promoted
一方では、この翠峰が昇進しているのを見ました
After solar reflection?
太陽光の反射後はどうなるでしょうか？
Yan dwarf overflows like a queen of heaven
ヤン小人は天国の女王のように溢れます
The fairy came out again
また妖精が出てきた
Then Yu Hui's kindness is a treasure
じゃあユ・フイの優しさは宝物だよ
Flickering among the clouds and Weng Yi
雲間のちらつきとウェン・イー
What list?
どのようなリストですか？
We only know the piano list
私たちはピアノのリストしか知りません
There is also a list here
こちらにもリストがあります
Bangda from the mountainside approx.
山の中腹から見たバンダ。
hollywood
ハリウッド
He used static
彼は静電気を使用しました
To translate the Land of Hollywood Land
Land of Hollywood Landを翻訳するには
just use this word
この言葉だけを使ってください
Let's take this from a modern movie
これを現代の映画から取り上げてみましょう
this sensuality
この官能性
Naturally, it is the same as the fairy needle sword in our traditional imagination
当然、我々の従来の想像における妖精針剣と同じものである。
A wonderful association arose
素敵なご縁が生まれました
Like this kind of tension between the text and the object of description
文章と記述対象との間のこの種の緊張感のように
a relationship that must be worked out
和らげなければならない関係
In Lu Bicheng's this
ルー・ビチェンのこれ
It can also be seen in the word
という言葉にも表れます
This Lu Bicheng wrote a lot of words in his overseas Jianwen
この盧碧成は海外の建文に多くの言葉を残しています。
This is also one of the reasons why later people have a high evaluation of his words.
これも後世の人々が彼の言葉を高く評価する理由の一つである。
Because it was impossible for other writers at that time
当時の他の作家には無理だったから
like he used such subjects
彼がそのような主題を使用したように
Let's look at an example
例を見てみましょう
This is what he wrote about the Eiffel Tower
これは彼がエッフェル塔について書いたものです
Then I won't read it either
だったら私も読まない
but look at
でも見てください
It's really old and new
本当に古くて新しいですね
Thousands of reds give birth to crows, afraid that the soul of spring will escape
春の魂が逃げるのを恐れて、何千ものアカがカラスを産む
But what about Kyushu first stationed in the sky to inspect
しかし、最初に空に駐留して視察した九州はどうだろうか
Iron to Ling Kong
鉄から霊孔へ
He was talking about the buildings of the station at that time
彼は当時の駅の建物について話していました
This is the benchmark of modern architecture
これが現代建築のベンチマークです
So he is very clever
だから彼はとても賢いんだ
The kind that combines modern architecture with classical nephrite thermostats
現代建築と古典的なネフライトサーモスタットを組み合わせたタイプ
imaginatively combined
想像力豊かに組み合わせた
Or look at the second
あるいは2番目を見てください
Do not turn over the old score
古いスコアをひっくり返さないでください
He took the Eiffel Tower
彼はエッフェル塔を取った
It is likened to this standard iron pillar
この標準的な鉄柱に見立てたもの
This is the Age of Empires
これは帝国の時代です
The pillar of the national border erected by the Eastern Han Dynasty
後漢時代に建てられた国境の柱
Is a symbol of the empire's industry
帝国産業の象徴です
Eiffel Tower
エッフェル塔
A symbol of industry compared to the traditional Chinese empire
伝統的な中華帝国と比較した産業の象徴
Stay in Sunny Days with Jin Xian in the Western Regions
ジン・シェンと一緒に晴れた日に西部地域に滞在
almost as high as the sun
太陽とほぼ同じ高さ
then look down
それから下を見てください
This car is as small as an ant
この車はアリのように小さいです
back around
周辺後方
So this lack of words for this blood tyrant from the iron tower
鉄の塔から来たこの血の暴君には言葉が足りません
very cleverly put this
これを非常に巧みに表現した
In his heart he can never let go
彼の心の中では決して手放すことはできない
Chinese classical tradition
中国の古典的な伝統
with what he has seen and heard in the West
彼が西洋で見聞きしたことについて
make a bond
絆を結ぶ
But always this combination
でもいつもこの組み合わせ
It seems to me that there is always friction
常に軋轢があるような気がする
But this friction also creates some fun
でも、この摩擦もまた楽しみを生むのです
Then Yubicheng wrote a lot of
それからユビチェンはたくさんのことを書きました
words from overseas
海外からの言葉
For example, he wrote about the lake in Geneva
たとえば、彼はジュネーブの湖について書いています。
Bingshan writes about the palace and so on.
冰山は宮殿のことなどを書いている。
So lest it often presents such a similar fun
似たような楽しみが頻繁に起こらないように
When we were reading Lu Bicheng's post
Lu Bicheng の投稿を読んでいたとき
You will find that as his Lu Cheng advances
彼の Lu Cheng が進歩するにつれて、それがわかるでしょう
He seems to be getting more and more tired of people
彼はますます人間に飽きているようだ
Become more and more alienated from human relationships
ますます人間関係から疎外されてしまう
Of course, this may be related to his growing religious feelings.
もちろん、これは彼の宗教的感情の高まりに関連しているかもしれません。
In the end he chose to live by Lake Geneva in Switzerland
最終的に彼はスイスのレマン湖畔に住むことを選びました。
Instead of returning to his original Lu-shaped center
元のルー型中心に戻るのではなく
Paris metropolitan to permanent residency
パリ大都市圏から永住権へ
I think this residency choice actually reflects
この居住地の選択は実際に反映されていると思います
Some changes in his own mood
彼自身の気分の変化
But we have to get back to reality
しかし、私たちは現実に戻らなければなりません
Regardless of whether Lu Bicheng is so rich
ルー・ビチェンがそんなに裕福かどうかは関係なく
Of course he is very rich to be able to do such a trip
もちろん、そのような旅行ができる彼はとても裕福です
but whether you have money or not
でもお金があるかどうかに関係なく
It doesn't matter it's the 1920s
1920年代だから関係ない
Or our 2010s today
あるいは2010年代の今日
To make a person whether a man or a woman
男でも女でも人を作るには
Traveling alone in a foreign country for a long time
外国に長期一人旅する場合
Actually it won't be one
実際には一つではないでしょう
easy is
簡単です
then this difficult
それからこれは難しい
this loneliness
この孤独
this feeling of loneliness
この孤独感
is a
です
We lobby for constant
私たちは恒常的にロビー活動を行います
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
is a time-traveling
タイムトラベルです
Leap across
飛び越える
across
横切って
even i want to cross race
私だって人種を越えたい
everyone on the go
外出中のみんな
there will be a general feeling
一般的な感覚があるだろう
I previously
私は以前
i forgot what time
何時か忘れた
But I remember I read a
しかし、私が読んだことを覚えています
read a british book
イギリスの本を読む
book about travel
旅行に関する本
in that book
その本の中で
he used several paintings
彼はいくつかの絵を使用した
Well, it just so happened that the painter
まあ、たまたまその画家は
Also one of my favorite painters
私の大好きな画家の一人でもあります
let me share with you
あなたと共有させてください
good
良い
This is also living in the 1919th century
これも1919世紀に生きている
Late to 20th century
20世紀後半から
about age
年齢について
left and right one
左右一個ずつ
contemporary british painters
現代イギリスの画家
sorry american painter
ごめんなさいアメリカの画家
Called Edward Hopper
エドワード・ホッパーと呼ばれる
What about him
彼についてはどうですか
My favorite painting is life
私の好きな絵は人生そのものです
maybe i believe
たぶん私は信じている
Everyone has seen his clothes painting
誰もが彼の服に絵を描いているのを見たことがあります
that is
あれは
On a street is a storefront
通りに店先がある
The inside of the store looks very bright
店内はとても明るい印象です
how many people are sitting inside
中には何人が座っていますか
But it seems bright
でも明るい気がする
but you just have a
しかし、あなたはただ持っています
endless
無限の
Empty
空
Feelings of consideration
思いやりの気持ち
Then what he expressed
そこで彼が表現したのは、
what about this emotion
この感情はどうでしょうか？
deeply moved me
私は深く感動しました
Then he often draws this kind of
それから彼はよくこんな感じの絵を描きます
The feeling of this consideration in the city
街中のこの配慮の感じ
And the feeling of consideration during the trip
そして旅先での思いやりの気持ち
Just now Wang Fu specifically mentioned
今、王福が具体的に言及しました
travel
旅行
train
訓練
hotel
ホテル
He actually contains all these things
彼には実際にこれらすべてが含まれています
A deep association and charm
深いつながりと魅力
It can be expressed in these paintings
この絵で表現できるのは
This is the journey he expressed
これが彼が表現した旅です
inside this
この中に
lonely
さみしい
isolated from others
他人から孤立している
feeling of inaccessibility
近づきがたい感覚
A sort of
一種
aphasia feeling
失語症の感覚
you can't talk to people
あなたは人と話すことができません
Or the feeling that there is no language at all
あるいは言語がまったく存在しないという感覚
will be in these paintings
これらの絵の中にいるでしょう
vaguely
漠然と
express it
それを表現する
What about these paintings?
これらの絵はどうでしょうか？
Must be from the 1920s
1920年代のものに違いない
we can see
見える
Some words are very clear
とても分かりやすい言葉があります
and it's all a woman
そしてそれはすべて女性です
It's clear she's on the road
彼女が外出中であることは明らかだ
For example, the upper left corner and the upper right corner follow
たとえば、左上隅と右上隅は次のようになります。
lower right corner
右下角
a woman on the go
外出中の女性
What about the lower left corner?
左下隅はどうでしょうか？
she didn't tell you she was traveling
彼女は旅行中だとあなたに言いませんでした
But what?
でも何？
do not know why
なぜだか分からない
I just feel like she's traveling
彼女が旅行しているような気がする
She is at a rest stop on a trip
彼女は旅行の途中の休憩所にいる
a resting place in the middle
中間一個休息的地方
no one to talk to
話す人がいない
Kuji
久慈
cold
寒い
We can see that
それがわかります
she
彼女
to get a coffee cup
コーヒーカップを手に入れるために
That's why I took off my gloves
だから手袋を外したんだ
but what about the other hand
しかし、もう一方の手はどうでしょうか
Some people carry such heavy
こんなに重いものを運ぶ人もいる
a glove
グローブ
She can't even take off her hat and clothes
彼女は帽子も服も脱ぐことができない
so cold so empty
とても寒いので空っぽです
so guji
だからぐじ
a feeling
感情
then every time you see
それから見るたびに
this
これ
Hopperized these
これらをホッパー化しました
What about female tourists?
女性観光客はどうですか？
Actually reminds me of 1920
実は1920年を思い出します
Tourist City Roaming in Europe and America
ヨーロッパとアメリカの観光都市放浪記
yes
はい
Li Bicheng also often wrote in his travel notes
李碧成も旅行記によく書いています。
He will come into contact with different people during this trip
彼はこの旅でさまざまな人たちと出会うだろう
For example, the person who sold him the ticket
たとえば、チケットを売った人
Or a passenger in the same car
または同じ車両の乗客
He also quarrels with passengers in the same car
彼は同じ車両の乗客と口論もする
Or a strange teenager who went with him to swim Lake Geneva
あるいはレマン湖のツアーに一緒に行った奇妙な少年
Wait, he's in contact with people
待って、彼は人々と連絡を取っている
But what about that feeling of loneliness and emptiness?
しかし、その孤独感や空虚感はどうでしょうか？
but never seemed to leave him
しかし決して彼から離れようとはしなかった
And what's interesting
そして何が面白いのか
What about his sense of isolation and ordering?
彼の孤立感と秩序の感覚はどうですか？
He often expresses it in a negative way
彼はよくそれを否定的な方法で表現します
For example, he would specifically write
たとえば、彼は具体的に次のように書きます。
Um
えーっと
When he travels, he often laughs at himself
彼は旅行するときよく自分自身を笑います
He'll say he's always smiling
彼はいつも笑顔だと言うだろう
Why because only one person doesn't smile so what
どうして、一人だけ笑わないから、どうして？
Well, the helplessness he showed
まあ、彼が見せた無力さは
ah one feels good
ああ、いい気分だ
or is it
またはそれは
He used a certain method to create a particularly deserted
彼はある方法を使って、特に人けのない場所を作りました。
or a particularly lively scene
または特に活気のあるシーン
But whether it's deserted or lively
でも、寂れていても、賑やかでも、
Lu Bicheng's figure as a lonely woman
孤独な女性としてのルー・ビチェンの姿
will be more prominent
もっと目立つようになるだろう
Let's look at two examples
2 つの例を見てみましょう
This is the first example
これが最初の例です
One time she was stuck in London
ある時、彼女はロンドンに行き詰まった
It's been half a year
半年が経ちました
she hates london
彼女はロンドンが嫌いです
Why
なぜ
It is clear
明らかです
At that time, the air pollution in London was very serious.
当時、ロンドンの大気汚染は非常に深刻でした。
Plus London is already foggy
それに、ロンドンはすでに霧がかかっています
When she was there, it was winter
彼女がそこにいたとき、それは冬でした
She is not used to the food
彼女はその食べ物に慣れていない
How about going to this Japanese restaurant in the alley next door for tofu?
豆腐を食べに隣の路地にある日本料理店に行ってみてはいかがでしょうか？
counting money piece by piece
お金を少しずつ数えます
she can't stand it
彼女はそれが我慢できない
How to do it
どうやってするの
she says
彼女が言います
Encounter, count the days, she knows this is
出会い、日数を数えて、彼女はこれがわかっている
Lunar cooking department
月の料理部
in China
中国で
Her relatives and friends should be celebrating
彼女の親戚や友人が祝ってくれるはずだ
at reunion
再会で
She is a solo artist
彼女はソロアーティストです
So what about Lu Bicheng?
では、ルー・ビチェンはどうでしょうか？
she says
彼女が言います
This is New Year's Eve
今日は大晦日です
So I dress myself up beautifully
だから私は自分を美しく着飾ります
I walked alone to the hotel's special restaurant to eat
ホテルの特別なレストランに一人で歩いて食事をした
what does he describe himself in
彼は自分自身を何と表現しますか
He is wearing a black section Hiratzu Hiratzu is a method of embroidery
黒い部分を着ているのが平津平津刺繍の技法です
This wrist coat embroidered with He, He, what a lonely image
He, Heと刺繍されたこのリストコートはなんとも寂しいイメージだ
The black segment is embroidered with golden hex
黒い部分には金色の六角形の刺繍が施されています
in golden shoes and bead jars
金の靴とビーズの瓶の中
He likes to wear pearls in a bead jar
彼はビーズの瓶に入った真珠を身に着けるのが好きです
He said it is very cheap to buy pearls in China
彼は、中国で真珠を買うのは非常に安いと言いました
wearing a bead jar
ビーズの瓶を身に着けている
like a fairy like a celestial being also like this image
妖精のような天体のようなこのイメージも
Go to the hotel's special restaurant
ホテルのスペシャルレストランへ
He said I look like I'm a fool
彼は私がバカみたいだと言った
That is to say, Hu Tianhudi means to look like a man in heaven
つまり、胡天湖帝とは天上の人に似ているという意味です。
It's not what people in the world mean
世の中の人が言いたいのはそういうことではない
Consider what he has built for himself
彼が自分のために何を築いてきたかを考えてみましょう
Such a deserted and lonely image
寒くて寂しいイメージ
image or vice versa at the busiest moment
最も混雑している時間帯の画像またはその逆
This is that he has finally arrived in Switzerland.
彼はついにスイスに到着したということです。
so he's there and he's just that rich
それで彼はそこにいる、そして彼はとても裕福です
He lives by the lake in Geneva
彼はジュネーブの湖のほとりに住んでいます
But he said that because of meeting Jieqing, the rest of the night
しかし彼は、ジエチンに会ったから、その夜の残りはそう言った
It's all from Guyue Xuantian, he can't do anything, he can't sleep at all
それはすべて Guyue Xuantin からのものです、彼は何もできず、まったく眠れません
So he felt that he was too lonely
だから彼はあまりにも孤独だと感じた
Because when you're alone, you're in this busy place where you're bothered
一人でいるときは、この忙しい場所にいると煩わしいからです
You will feel more sick, not to mention he is not worried about poverty
あなたはさらに気分が悪くなるでしょう、言うまでもなく彼は貧困について心配していません
As for why he puts his worries on poverty, of course, that's another matter.
もちろん、なぜ彼が貧困を懸念しているのかというと、それはまた別の問題だ。
So it’s okay to pretend you can’t hear me, what should I do in the end?
聞こえないふりでもいいけど、結局どうすればいいの？
He just decided to say, then I'll join them.
彼はただ、「なら私も彼らに加わる」と決心したのです。
So which issue of his costume did he pay so much attention to his image?
それで、彼は自分のイメージにそれほど注意を払ったドレスの何号でしょうか？
I still have to dress up, dress up before going out
まだドレスアップしなきゃ、出かける前にドレスアップして
then just
その後
just go outside for a walk
ただ散歩に外に出てください
found outside
外で見つけた
From people like branches, lanterns and bamboo sky
枝、提灯、竹の空のような人々から
Red and green rubber halo on the lake surface, pearls of water blooming
湖面に赤と緑のゴムの後光が浮かび上がり、真珠の水が輝きます
Unique banquet
ユニークな宴会
at this time
現時点では
This is Baihuahui
ここは百華匯です
this festival
この祭り
All of them are holding a paper bag inside
中には全員が紙袋を持っています
All tax-deductible materials
すべての税控除対象物
lose when you see someone
誰かを見たら負ける
Seems like they're not splashing water
水しぶきはかからないようです
They are just splash material
ただのスプラッシュ素材です
So
それで
Even the body of the police will be thrown away is the material
警察の死体も捨てられるのが材料だ
that law does not prohibit
その法律は禁止していない
So
それで
what did he say
彼が何を言ったの
what about this time
今回はどうですか
Both father and daughter are wearing bags
父も娘もバッグをかぶっています
And the collars are big
そして襟が大きい
so
それで
Once the material is thrown away?
材料は一度捨てられますか？
They all ran into the clothes
全員が服にぶつかった
So
それで
Some people will pull this collar off of others
この首輪を他の人から引き離す人もいます
Then what
じゃあ何
Pour all the materials in
材料をすべて投入します
So
それで
Someone deliberately patted someone on the shoulder
誰かが故意に誰かの肩をたたいた
As soon as you look back, quickly put this material
振り返ったらすぐにこの資料をさっと置いてください
Throw it in someone's face, etc.
人の顔に投げつけるなど。
this prank goes
このいたずらは行きます
Then he was thrown out
それから彼は追い出されました
made him that this
彼にこれをさせた
I can't keep my eyes open
目を開けていられない
It's like he's at war
まるで戦争中のようだ
he lost
彼は負けました
he fled back to the hotel
彼はホテルに逃げ帰った
he said it doesn't matter
彼はそれは関係ないと言った
i'm ready tomorrow
明日の準備はできています
again
また
So the next day he took the weapon himself
それで翌日、彼は自ら武器を手に取った
Just a bag of material
材料袋だけ
Then there's a towel over it
その上にタオルがかぶせられています
pretend you don't have a weapon
武器を持っていないふりをする
wait until someone walks in
誰かが入ってくるまで待ちます
It was only then that I suddenly threw this material on someone else.
そのとき初めて、私は突然このネタを他の人に投げつけました。
Then he is particularly visual
それから彼は特にビジュアルが優れています
To describe how he participated in the Hundred Flowers Festival
百花繚乱に参加した経緯を説明する
How do you hang out with everyone?
みんなとはどうやって交流していますか？
we can really imagine
私たちは本当に想像することができます
The hotel where I was alone in London
ロンドンで一人だったホテル
But also stubbornly wear beaded gold and aluminum
しかし、ビーズの金やアルミニウムも頑固に着用します
This must-see city in the lake, sky and lake
必見のこの湖と空と湖の街
Arrived at the Hundred Flowers Festival
百花祭りに到着
but he wants to let go
しかし彼は手放したいと思っています
chasing after the crowd like a child
子どものように群衆を追いかける
Passionate about planting this material
この材料を植えることに情熱を注ぐ
In fact, the loneliness of that journey
実はその旅の孤独は
It's not bothering me at all
全然気にしてないよ
Or lighten up with laughing scenes
または笑いシーンで明るくする
Instead, we see more
代わりに、もっと見ることができます
the sorrow in his heart
彼の心の中の悲しみ
The loneliness of the figure
姿の孤独
Against the backdrop of this external joyful environment
この楽しい外部環境を背景に
In fact, it is more prominent
実際はもっと目立つんですが
The interesting thing is that Lu Bicheng said
興味深いのは、ルー・ビチェンがこう言ったことです。
This Hundred Flowers War is actually an elegant battle
この百花戦争は実は優雅な戦いなのです
everyone is silent
誰もが沈黙している
Because all the people here are international
ここにいる人たちはみんな国際色豊かだから
We don't speak the same language
私たちは同じ言語を話せません
So it's right to throw away the paper if you borrow it.
したがって、誰かに借りた場合は、その紙を捨ててください。
no need to speak
話す必要はありません
so you can also say
だからあなたも言うことができます
For Lu Bicheng
ルー・ビチェンの場合
This is the most convenient way to integrate into a foreign country
これは外国に溶け込む最も便利な方法です
Because you just open yourself up
あなたは自分自身を開くだけだから
You don't need to be able to communicate in language
言語コミュニケーションができる必要はない
can be integrated into the environment
環境に統合できる
At the end of the Hundred Flowers Conference
百花会議の終わりに
Lu Bicheng also made it very clear
Lu Bicheng 氏も明確に述べました
He said that night
その夜彼は言いました
like a dream
夢のような
After all, his life experience is in vain
結局のところ、彼の人生経験は無駄だ
identity of his culture
彼の文化のアイデンティティ
His love on this journey
この旅における彼の愛
His self-admiration and so on
彼の自画自賛など
They can only temporarily participate in such a Hundred Flowers Conference
そんな百花会議には一時的にしか参加できない
just be liberated
ただ解放されてください
What about after the big dream trip?
夢の大旅行の後はどうですか？
He is still going back to the home of the wandering lonely traveler
彼は今も放浪する孤独な旅人の家に帰ります
in this situation
この状況では
Of course it's in his mail
もちろん彼のメールに書いてあります
Also mentioned a lot of this more practical issue
このより現実的な問題についても多く言及しました
For example, how can I get into trouble booking a ticket?
たとえば、チケットの予約でトラブルが発生する可能性はありますか?
sometimes dangerous
時には危険な
In fact, traveling alone
実は一人旅
Of course it can be dangerous
もちろん危険なこともあります
Then Lu Bicheng is in the post office
それからルー・ビチェンは郵便局にいる
Keep mentioning that he's actually in constant danger
彼は実際に常に危険にさらされていると言い続けます
Unknowingly or luckily escaped
無意識に、あるいは幸運にも逃げ出すことができた
Here's another story lurking out there
そこにはもう一つの物語が潜んでいる
Of course I don't have time to share with you today
もちろん、今日はあなたと共有する時間がありません
The highest point of Lu Bicheng's mailing
Lu Bicheng のメールの最高点
It should be when he was in 1929
彼が1929年にいた頃のはずだ
Accepted the invitation of the World Animal Protection Association
世界動物保護協会の招待を受諾
to vienna for the congress
会議のためにウィーンへ
At this time Lu Bicheng is a very devout Buddhist
現時点では、ルー・ビチェンは非常に敬虔な仏教徒です
He sang that vegetarian food does not kill
彼はベジタリアンフードは人を殺さないと歌った
But he attended the conference as a
しかし、彼は会議に出席した
and the public speaking guests
そして講演のゲストたち
We still see this image
このイメージは今でも見られます
The person is the one who wears pearls, steps on golden shoes, and eyebrow pencil
その人は真珠を身に着け、金の靴を踏み、そしてアイブロウペンシルを持っている人です
The image of Lu Bicheng dressed like a peacock
孔雀の格好をしたヨ・ビソンのイメージ
So he will always insist on literary creation
だから彼は常に文学創作に固執するだろう
Writing classical Chinese and old poems
漢詩や古詩を書く
seems to be i independent
私は独立しているようです
He will always write in an old style
彼はいつも古いスタイルで書くだろう
So it is often classified as a conservative in literature
そのため文学界では保守派に分類されることが多い
or old hands
または古い手
Well, on the surface
まあ、表面的には
He is this maverick in terms of behavior
彼は行動という点では異端者だ
Then his behavior and his insistence on style
それから彼の行動とスタイルへのこだわり
It seems that if we just said at the beginning
最初に言ってしまったらそうなる気がする
Looks like it's been stolen or contradicted
盗用か矛盾しているようです
But in fact, we might as well think about it the other way around
しかし実際には、逆に考えてみてもいいかもしれません
When he stands in such a mighty modern
彼がこのような強力な現代に立ったとき、
when inside the red oil of the times
時代の赤い油の中にいるとき
does he want it
彼はそれを望んでいますか
just indifferent
ただ無関心なだけ
but he is not
しかし彼はそうではありません
so what
だから何
He is like Lu Bicheng
彼はルー・ビチェンに似ています
there is such a non-inquiry
このような非問い合わせがあります
a rebellious personality
反抗的な性格
Only in such a powerful
このような強力な場合にのみ、
Stick to a certain kind of trend in an era
ある時代のトレンドに固執する
what he believes
彼が信じていること
then finally
それから最後に
as a conclusion
結論として
get out of the house
家から出る
Travel from abroad
海外からの旅行
life journey
人生の旅
literary travel
文学旅行
China travel experience
中国旅行体験談
In fact, there are various
実は色々あるのですが、
face
顔
My speech today is just to choose
今日の私のスピーチはただ選択することです
Lu Bicheng's European and American Tours
ルー・ビチェンのヨーロッパとアメリカのツアー
as the center
中心として
Of course this is because
もちろんこれがあるからです
character who goes by himself
一人で行動するキャラクター
Also because of his works to this day
また、今日までの彼の作品のおかげで、
let us appreciate
感謝しましょう
complete place
完全な場所
And more noticeably
そしてさらに顕著なのは
active in the 19th century
19世紀に活躍した
turn of the second century
2世紀の変わり目
women of literature
文学者の女性たち
Lu Bicheng, I think
ルー・ビチェンだと思います
really has some kind of key meaning
実はある種の重要な意味を持っている
he obviously
彼は明らかに
cant
できない
simply to inspire
単にインスピレーションを与えるため
progress
進捗
We are more simplistic today
今日はもっと単純化しています
label to define him
彼を定義するラベル
why
なぜ
Because from some of the examples we just climbed
なぜなら、いくつかの例から私たちはたった今登ったばかりだからです
you can see
見ることができます
It actually continues upwards
実は上に向かって続いているんです
The literary aesthetics of classical women
古典的な女性の文学的美学
And a heart and will to explore outward
そして外へ探求する一種の心と意志
Down it actually opened the modern
実際に下に行くとモダンな空間が開きました
We can even say that it means contemporary
それは現代を意味しているとも言えます
Roaming New Meaning of Travel
ローミング 旅の新しい意味
The travels it does and the writing it mails
旅をしたりメールで文章を書いたり
the kind of many women of its generation
同世代の多くの女性のようなもの
purposeful travel
目的のある旅行
In fact, there is a separation
実は別れがあるんです
I want to use a special example today
今日は特別な例を使いたいと思います
Back and forth to the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明と清の時代を行ったり来たり
and down to our contemporary experience
そして私たちの現代の経験に至るまで
Share it with everyone
みんなと共有しましょう
My observations and understanding of Chinese women's travel experience
中国人女性の旅行経験に関する私の観察と理解
with feelings
感情とともに
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you for talking nonsense
長話ありがとう
then he speaks brilliantly
それから彼は見事に話します
we have about ten minutes
10分ほど時間があります
I don't know who's going to finish
誰が終わるか分からない
good time
良い時間
Simple
単純
short
短い
if there is a problem, just say
問題がある場合は、言ってください
just said it again and again
ただ何度も言いました
he is classified as handy
彼は器用な人に分類される
because of his problem
彼の問題のせいで
But his hands are so-called, they are actually too attractive
でも彼の手はいわゆる、実は魅力的すぎるんです
Those who criticized him at the time
当時彼を批判していた人々
rebellious for his attraction
彼の魅力に対して反抗的
he doesn't want to start hurtful behavior
彼は有害な行為を始めたくない
Don't you think your criticism is contradictory?
あなたの批判は矛盾していると思いませんか？
What do these critics think of
これらの批評家は何を考えていますか
His behavior attracts hands with his questions
彼の行動は質問の手を惹きつける
so this thing
それでこのこと
Thanks
ありがとう
What I just said is actually a
私が今言ったことは、実は、
The name of the later construction
その後の工事の名称
His contemporaries don't think so
彼の同時代人はそうは思わない
For example he was
たとえば彼はこうだった
Posted in so many news
たくさんのニュースに掲載されました
What was in the media at the time
当時メディアで取り上げられた内容
It's what I just said is very popular.
先ほど言ったものは非常に人気があります。
So we'll see in hindsight
それで後から考えてみましょう
When we went to see him in later literary history
後の文学史で彼に会いに行ったとき
will be like this
そうなるだろう
He would be classified as such
彼はそのように分類されるだろう
what old hands
何という古い手
Or can't innovate
あるいはイノベーションができない
Or let's say what we see in contemporary times
あるいは現代で私たちが見ているものを言ってみましょう
a modern critic would say
現代の批評家ならこう言うだろう
in his overseas neologisms
彼の海外の新造語では
Although I have written so many Western things
西洋のことをたくさん書いてきましたが、
but just one
でも一つだけ
he never left
彼は決して離れなかった
his Chinese classical
彼の中国古典
we will see criticism like this
このような批判を見ることになるでしょう
with his western sword
彼の西洋剣で
the spark
スパーク
that's where it gets interesting
そこが興味深いところです
It’s not that he must give up Chinese classical
中国古典を諦めなければならないわけではない
Or he must embrace the western Jianwen
あるいは西側の建文を受け入れなければならない
that genre follows
そのジャンル
The one produced between his sword texts
彼の剣のテキストの間に生成されたもの
The contradiction is
矛盾は
is where he's really interesting
そこが彼の本当に興味深いところだ
personally
個人的に
ask for advice
アドバイスを求める
Just mentioned that Li Bichen
先ほどリー・ビチェンについて言及しました
he
他
before going to san francisco
サンフランシスコに行く前に
used to visit
よく訪れた
he went to san francisco first
彼は最初にサンフランシスコに行きました
not go first
最初に行かないでください
San Francisco
サンフランシスコ
then to
それから
His name is Luo Sheng
彼の名前はルオ・シェンです
Rosander
ロサンダー
then go to hollywood
それからハリウッドに行きます
going to hollywood
ハリウッドに行く
Said he was dreaming
彼は夢を見ていると言った
Go to Nan Xingxing's business card and give him
Nan Xingxing の名刺のところに行き、彼に渡します
Li Bichen
リー・ビチェン
Did he ever yearn for
彼は憧れたことがあるだろうか
maybe
多分
gonna be a hollywood star
ハリウッドスターになるだろう
Is there such a record
そんな記録あるのか
Thanks
ありがとう
Is there such a record?
そんな記録あるの？
I don't seem to have seen such a record
そんな記録は見たことがないようです
But he's really a star
でも彼は本当にスターだよ
except he's not hollywood
彼がハリウッドではないことを除いて
quiet star
静かな星
Thank you very much for your thoughts
ご意見ありがとうございます
Today you presented this
今日はこちらをご紹介いただきました
trip
旅行
But we also know that in the late 19th or early 20th century
しかし、19 世紀後半または 20 世紀初頭には
There are many Chinese laborers going to Southeast Asia or to Europe and the United States
東南アジアやヨーロッパ、アメリカへ向かう中国人労働者がたくさんいる
Then they are an underground class
それなら彼らは地下階級だ
Then it was also during this period that women began to
そして、女性がこうなり始めたのもこの時期でした。
It may be because the male goes out first to follow the son or the husband.
男性が息子や夫を追って先に出かけるからかもしれません。
And to the United States or to Southeast Asia
そしてアメリカや東南アジアへ
that their trip
彼らの旅行は
If we take their outings as travel
彼らの外出を旅行とすると
their travel experience will be very different
彼らの旅行体験は大きく変わるでしょう
I don’t know if it’s in your research
あなたの研究の中にあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
Is there any travel involved in this area?
この地域には旅行が関係していますか?
is underground
地下にあります
This alarm is easy to guess
この警報は推測しやすい
sore feet because
足が痛いので
because i'm from doing this star feminist literature
なぜなら、私はこのスターフェミニスト文学の出身だからです
Or until the end of the Qing Dynasty and the beginning of the Ming Dynasty
あるいは清朝の終わりから明朝の初めまで
The phenomenon of some so-called female writers in the literary world
文壇のいわゆる女性作家たち
I must admit I'm really relatively untouched by this upper middle class
正直、私はこの上位中産階級の影響をあまり受けていないことを認めなければなりません
Beyond the experience of women's lives
女性の人生経験を超えて
The one I'm sharing with you today
今日あなたにシェアするのは
content
コンテンツ
at most it is about
せいぜいそれくらいです
Activities in Jingxiang
京郷のアクティビティ
Participated by non-elite women
エリート以外の女性も参加
But I must also regret to say
しかし、残念なことも言わなければなりません
Just that example
まさにその例
also by male authors
男性作家によるものも
presented with a critical eye
批判的な目で提示された
So as for women of that class
それで、そのクラスの女性については
when she engages in activities like that
彼女がそのような活動に従事するとき
her own
彼女自身の
no matter how
どんなに
I feel good
良い感じ
She has good experience
彼女は良い経験を持っています
I
私
I haven't done any research myself
自分では何も調べていない
then i too
それなら私も
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
what material to use
どのような材料を使用するか
can come to explore
探検に来ることができます
this aspect of this matter
この問題のこの側面
this is real
これは本物です
beyond my ability
私の能力を超えた
terribly sorry
大変申し訳ありません
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, I’m the author and I can’t understand it, but it’s very interesting to listen to tonight
ありがとう、私は作者なので理解できませんが、今夜聞くのはとても興味深いです
One problem I have is that your head is all purple
一つ問題があるのは、あなたの頭が紫色になっていることです
Your clothes are also purple, so it doesn't matter if I carry them
服も紫だから背負っても大丈夫
In fact, if my colleagues know that the background color of the POWER POINT I use recently is this color
実は最近使っているパワーポイントの背景色がこの色であることを同僚に知られたら
Because I think it has a dark background, so it highlights the front
背景が暗いので正面が強調されていると思います
That's the only reason the dress was just casually worn this morning when it was too late
それが、今朝手遅れだったときにそのドレスが何気なく着られた唯一の理由です
just a coincidence
ただの偶然
I think just now Director Hu showed the rich clothing images of women since the Ming and Qing Dynasties
ちょうど今、胡監督が明清時代以来の女性の豊かな服装の画像を見せたと思います。
travel is a big subject i'm not researching this but travel is a big subject
旅行は大きなテーマです これについては調査していませんが、旅行は大きなテーマです
In 1932 or the 1930s, Academia Sinica had an early
1932 年または 1930 年代に、中央研究院は初期の
But he really seemed to be just an editor named Jiang Shaoyuan who wrote an article
しかし、彼は実際には記事を書いた江少源という名前の単なる編集者に見えました
Ancient Chinese Travel Studies
古代中国の旅行学
Look inside and talk about ancient travel
中を覗いて古代の旅について話しましょう
full of superstition
迷信に満ちている
use many mysterious means
数々の謎の手段を使う
To prevent bad luck from happening, etc.
不運が起こらないようにするためなど。
So the whole trip is a
つまり、旅行全体は
A very complicated and dangerous process
非常に複雑で危険なプロセス
But this book pays little attention to
しかし、この本ではほとんど注意が払われていない
But there are many books like this
でもこういう本はたくさんある
It is also worth referring to our elves today
今日のエルフについても言及する価値があります
When painstaking efforts of Haruki are always fashionable
ハルキハルキのひと手間がいつもオシャレに
Travel is an important means for their spiritual progress
旅行は彼らの霊的進歩のための重要な手段です
Because you have to meet different people when you go out
外に出ると色々な人に会わなければならないので
different realms
異なる領域
so travel
だから旅行する
But it's different from what he said today
でも今日彼が言ったこととは違います
Nonsense Zhang is talking about another stage
ナンセンスな張氏は別のステージについて話している
Another form of this trip
この旅のもう一つの形
I think he spoke very well today
今日彼はとても上手に話せたと思う
I've been watching what he's looking at paper
私は彼が紙を見ているのをずっと見ていた
I thought there was an article
記事があったと思ってた
because he speaks well
彼はよく話すので
He noticed that the birth of a child is a chapter of this
彼は、子供の誕生がこの問題の一章であることに気づきました。
Later I found out that there is no, he actually seems to be an article, right?
後で知ったのですが、実は彼は記事になっているそうですよ？
is relevant
関連がある
related
関連している
related related material
関連関連資料
Li Bicheng of course
もちろん李碧成
I'm only here and there are a lot of things about him.
私はここにいるだけで、彼についてはたくさんのことがあります。
Frankly speaking, I always thought he was with
率直に言って、私はいつも彼がいると思っていました
People like Hu Yingmeng
胡英夢のような人
Do you know Hu Yingmeng?
胡英夢さんをご存知ですか？
He and many important people in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China
彼と清朝末期および中華民国の多くの重要人物
They all had contacts, and the earliest was with the most famous
彼ら全員に連絡先があり、最も古いのは最も有名な人との連絡先でした。
The latest sciences together, like logic, etc.
ロジックなどの最新科学が一堂に会します。
So there are many in the original father who are related to Li Bicheng
つまり、元の父親には李碧成と関係のある人がたくさんいます
Many people had two burns. The original father and others mentioned it.
２度の火傷を負った人も多く、初代の父親などが言及していた。
But this Uncle Hu showed another name today.
しかし、この胡おじさんは今日、別の名前を示しました。
I knew very little about this side
こちら側についてはほとんど知りませんでした
It's because I listened to his speech today.
それは今日彼のスピーチを聞いたからです。
I'm very proud of myself, too. Thank you.
私も自分自身をとても誇りに思います、ありがとう
Well we just missed you today thank you
さて、今日はあなたがいなくて寂しかったです、ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう